0011648518	Is there a problem? Please, Asmarael must be confronted!
0033827678	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 2
0033827679	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 3
0033827680	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 4
0033827681	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 5
0040924459	What are you doing here? You're out to steal the Great Machine!<br><br>This area is off limits to all except the guardians! There can be only FOUR!
0085251768	<b><i>2 Jankar 4158</i></b><br><br>Today marks the 3rd month anniversary since the beginning of the war against the alien invaders. The world of Ancaria has taken significant losses already. The Ancarian Unification Council's Science Division has put me in charge of harnessing T-Energy and creating a weapon to defeat the invaders.<br><br>As near as anyone has been able to figure, the invasion started not long after the near tragic portal accident in the Orcish territory of Nor Plat. The explosion in the heavens above Ancaria apparently caused a rupture in space and time, and when our world came within range a large contingent of what can only be referred to as 'monstrosities' crossed over into our world. Monstrosities of every size and shape that are as difficult to kill as the germs that cause Black Fever.<br><br><b><i>3 Jankar 4158</i></b><br><br>Today, Seraphim Maria and her Primad squad of warriors managed to fell one of the invaders. It wasn't quite dead when they brought it in to the hospital at Ciria Delith. We were ordered to examine the beast and find out what makes it tick. Surprisingly, at first it appears to be very similar to life forms we're familiar with. One head, two arms, two legs... Of course, their elongated heads, slavering jaws and foul acidic breath speak otherwise. Several of the Seraphim that brought the beast in today had fairly horrific acid burns on various parts of their bodies. Fortunately, their combat healing potions helped keep them from getting anything worse than a few nasty scars.<br><br>Apparently, the acid it spits is part of its food intake mechanism. It spits out a nasty dose of acidic poison that immobilizes and eventually kills its prey as well as begins to predigest the victim. The slavering jaws extend from its mouth to latch onto the victim where the creature begins sucking in the pre-digested flesh of said victim much like an Ancarian sucker fly's proboscis.<br><br>First T-rays show that the internal arrangement of the alien seems to be a bit different from most Ancarian life. The exoskeletal arrangement of the creature seems to indicate it's an insectoid. It seems to have four lungs that function much like our hearts – two chambers take in air, while the other two handle the exhaust.<br><br>All in all, these beings, while they're exoskeletal structure are like built-in armor, they're not impossible to kill. The information has been forwarded to the appropriate departments.<br><br><b><i>18 Jankar 4158</i></b><br><br>Maria and her Primad squad brought in another specimen for our research. This one appears to be fish-like except that it doesn't appear to live in water. It floats above the ground. How exactly it manages this defies logic. Since this one was quite dead, we were able to dissect it. We didn't find anything within its body to suggest how it can just float in the air. Clearly, this is something NOT of this world.<br><br><b><i>19 Jankar 4158</i></b><br><br>The alien is dead. Our captive seems to have decided to commit suicide. It refused to eat. Even live sheep, goats and other animals couldn't tempt it to feed. Either that or the animals in question were just not appetizing to our 'guest'.<br><br><b><i>21 Jankar 4158</i></b><br><br>The autopsy on our 'guest' was completed. What a putrid mess! Apparently, the creature was not entirely immune to its own toxic juices. It apparently swallowed some of its own acidic poison spittle and the toxins and acid ate parts of it from within. It would seem that normally, the acids would be partially neutralized when it comes into contact with the flesh of its prey. Unfortunately, the exoskeleton is not affected by the acidic compounds. So even if we were able to reproduce the acid and find a viable delivery method, it wouldn't likely have much of an effect.<br><br>It took a lot of effort to crack the shell open. We finally brought in a 50 tonne press to get the job done. Too bad, we can't ask these monstrosities to step inside one of these presses one by one so we can kill them. I doubt they would be willing to cooperate. As it is, the press damn near broke. It might work for one, maybe two of the beasts, but there are at least a few thousand of them all over Ancaria.
0124787659	The Wrong Path
0138813799	Back to the cave!<br><br>Psst! Please, come over here, so my father Tallin can not hear us now. I have lied to both of you. These small spiders we encountered inside the cave were not the reason for all this nightmare. The source is still there. Please return to the cave and destroy it once and for all.
0138999525	That's all you could find? Well, that should be enough for a few decent swords. Oh yes, take your reward.
0213843385	The spiders are late. I mean, late spiders. We safely returned to Skook's Corner. All the way back she was glancing at me weirdly and now she looks very confused, nothing like a hero who has just accomplished a great task. Something still troubles her. I should ask her about it.
0217097697	Sounds like I was right. To make things more interesting, the evil counterpart is an old friend of Failitia! I was urged to be cautious. Failitia, or Asmarael has some tricks up her sleeve. Into the cave! Let's see if this Asmarael is home.
0219172468	All Attributes
0228730326	Follow the dark side.<br><br>Wait... I have a proposition. Lets turn the table on her. Dispose of her and you will we generously rewarded. What say you?
0234330550	Yes! I have managed to defeat Asmarael. Though this was not an easy victory, her evil shall taint the world of Ancaria no longer! I should tell Failitia the good news.
0284446435	What the...! Is no one here what they seem to be? What have I gotten myself in to?
0307192210	What? That guy over there is whispering something I cannot understand. Damn pointed ears... I guess he was eavesdropping on my conversation with Giles. So let's see what he wants from me.
0328259903	<b><i><AlignH Value=Center/>A Northland Tale</i></b><br><br><AlignH Value=Left/><i>"By Lumen endowed, by Lumen protected!"</i><br><br>Thorbrand Kal'Dur, son to lord Magnus Kal'Dur, lord of the Northern Isle of Ice, was born under the second moon of winter. To his people, this was a sign of coming greatness. Thorbrand would be one of the greatest heroes they had ever known. To his great misfortune, he was regarded and revered as such already, yet no great deeds had found him yet. Not that he did not look for opportunities. He would embark with his fellow warriors to plague the lands of Artamark time upon time, but to him it seemed he was just one of the warriors. Nothing special!<br><br>The raids would come and go, the plunder and loot would differ every time, but with every return to his home, Thorbrand's mood grew darker. How was he to be what was expected of him?<br><i>"Becoming the greatest of his people, when he had nothing to present than some mere loot and tales of victory?"</i><br><br>With one of his darker moods, Thorbrand wandered into the northern reaches of the Isle. A savage, uninhabited reach of mountains, plagued by bitter cold winds and only few known places for shelter. He had passed all of those places, when he felt a great storm gathering strength.<br><br>He cursed into his beard:<br><i>"Bah! Thorbrand Kal'Dur, the "great hero" of the Northern Isle, killed in a mere storm! What a tale would that make!"</i><br><br>Muttering on, his eyes searched the mountains for a possible hideout, where he could weather the storm. And sure enough, a distance up the mountain he was climbing, he saw what could be a cave. Hard to see, as snowflakes were filling the sky so fast, that he would soon be unable to see anything. Picking up his pace, both to reach safety and stay warm, he hurried up the mountain, knowing that if his eyes had betrayed him, it would be for the last time.<br><br>A sigh of great relief escaped him, when he reached what was indeed a cave. As he entered, he realized that this was not just a cave. It was not big, but it shone with a blue light. Searching for the source of this light, he found an altar where clearly this light was radiating from.<br><br>Upon the altar he found an axe so beautiful, that he immediately felt awed.<br><br>Inscribed upon the handle, in blue letters pulsing with inner light, was:<br><br><i>"By Lumen endowed, by Lumen protected"</i><br><br>He read, knowing that this was the most special weapon he had ever seen, nor ever would see. A veritable weapon of the Gods!<br><br><AlignH Value=Center/><Image=kaldursaxe.tga/><br> <br><AlignH Value=Left/><i>"Aen lífdagar, aen rata tar sjá øx. Minn vilja elta ar nauðsyn, eða selja réttr jafnaðr!"</i>* he said, as his hand closed around the hilt, never to let go of it in his entire life.*("If it liveth, it shall fall to my axe. I shall pursue as needed, and exact rightful punishment!")<br><br>When the storm had subsided, and Thorbrand had returned home with his new weapon, his tale began. Although he noticed that raids, plundering and pillaging where a thing of the past. Wielding this mighty axe, he could do only good. He would wander the lands of Ancaria, searching out those that were in need of help. Nothing could withstand his mighty axe, as it seemed that with every swing, he grew stronger, and his foe weaker. Man and beast fell to his axe. He was even known for slaying the great white dragon of the North.<br><br>Years upon years had he hunted evil, the axe bestowing him with an unnatural prolonged life, when tales of his heroic deeds were still plentiful, but no longer swelling. No new feats of heroism reached the ears of the people of Ancaria. Thorbrand Kal'Dur, the greatest hero of all time, was gone, and never seen or heard of again.<br><br>Although a great many adventurer has gone off in search of his fabled axe, Thorbrand or "Kal'Dur's Legacy" has yet to be found again...
0354415691	A Sword of Light and Darkness
0385634440	What an encounter! Failitia, the Dreamweaver, closest friend to Sophia and one of the oldest and wisest beings in Ancaria. What an honor. Besides the fact that light triumphed, I also got rewarded handsomely!
0386928997	A Northland Tale
0419022943	Asmarael is truly evil! I will have to fight her, as she will not stand down. The light must have victory this day!
0493926407	Finally! I found Seriefa. It is about time I got to the bottom of this.
0521145103	I got quite a nice reward for helping to dispatch that monster. Tizz'Agoz threw something extra in here along with the reward money.
0538384085	Sorry Failitia, but it seems your payment was not high enough!
0551604260	It's done, praise the Gods! The mutated dragon will no longer threaten Ancaria. I will honor my end of the bargain, traveler. No matter your requirements, I will be able to provide elite mounts to you, far beyond the abilities of anything else you've seen. Please, browse my stock, and best of luck to you.
0584665101	Prepare for a tough fight.<br><br>I should warn you though. This so called Failitia is no ordinary human. Besides the obvious dark criminal, she is a sorceress and a summoner. She is the evil Spiderqueen. We once knew her as Asmarael, and she was part of our little band. Sadly, she turned to a darker side of the magic she wielded. We have crossed paths since then. Several times in fact. If anything, I know this will be dangerous. She is bent on ruining my reputation... that and even worse. She has to be stopped! Will you help me?
0645333939	Bah, I should have known she wasn't called the 'Spiderqueen' for nothing!
0688293458	Inside the cave I encountered a giant spider that might came directly from the depths of hell. Now I can understand the reason behind all the fear and panic that has worried the locals for generations. It was a very tough fight, but victory is mine. I will tell Lydia about my success, but first I have to take the cobwebs off my arms...
0775343127	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 1
0828618289	You made it back alive! I'm shocked! Er... pardon the expression. Here is the bounty for killing the lightning elemental. Good luck on your journey. I hope we meet again.
0828658005	Troll Grounds
0843609403	<b><i>1 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>I finally got a chance to plead my case in front of the Ministry of Warfare with regards to sentient experimentation. They were practically shaking in their boots with the reports that were filtering in from all over Ancaria. It was an easy sell, what with the arguments Keriana has supplied me with. The beaurocrats had one stipulation, though. They would only send volunteers.<br><br><b><i>2 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>Our new lab in the west won't be ready for some time, so our first experiments will have to be done in our current facility. The first volunteer arrived today at the Na'Fian portal on the west side of the city. He isn't exactly a striking figure. Below average build. An engineer, background in the fundamental science. I questioned him about why he volunteered. He said he had nothing to lose. He'd been ill and didn't have very long to live. Something about a war injury that never quite healed right. Ahh, well... As long as he survives the infusion...<br><br><b><i>4 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>Our T-Energy tank is fully stocked. Our volunteer is prepped and ready.<br><br><b><i>4 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>Test Subject A's infusion was... interesting to say the least. His infusion drained the entire tank's worth of T-Energy. He is about 1.5 times as large as he was before, much larger than a typical Ancarian High Elf. And he is quite blue, similar in shading to our dearly departed Algernon and Ben. He retained his memories and knowledge. He knows where he is and what's been done to him. He's been eating like a wild beast. We've estimated so far, he's eaten approximately 14 average dinners in the space of a few hours. There doesn't seem to be any evidence of his previous injury. The T-Energy appears to have healed him. It appears Test A was a success.<br><br><b><i>5 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>The first of the interdimensional aliens arrived in Ciria Delith this morning near the Temple of Tears in the east. It was one of those flying monstrosities and it called itself a "Sakkarim". It appears to be sentient as well. It demanded our unconditional surrender with the obligatory "or else"...<br><br>Our Test A subject decided to face the monster. He arrived at the surface and calmly walked through the throng of people attempting to flee west. People thought it kind of strange to see a rather oversized blue glow in the dark High Elf calmly walking toward the danger they were fleeing and stopped in their tracks. They did not follow our champion who stopped a few horse lengths from the invader and simply raised his arms and a large number of Fen Fires appeared out of nowhere and swarmed the invader and promptly exploded as they collided with the target. The monstrosity collapsed from the Fen Fires hit it wave after wave with what seemed like ruthless abandon. After his victory the Test A subject summoned a few waves of the Fen Fires and dispersed them amongst the people who were injured by the beast. The Fen Fires promptly healed their injuries. The people were in awe of our first test subject. Some even bowed in prayer. Amazing.<br><br><b><i>6 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>Our test subject returned to the lab and promptly devoured half of a roast hog, generously donated by an eatery owner who was about to be stepped on by the Sakkara monster but was saved by the hero of the hour. Speaking of our hero... He has decided he needs a name. He's decided that his old name and identity just won't do as he has changed so drastically. He's decided that since he is the product of Test A, he would like to be known as Testa from now on.<br><br>Testa is now in the process of reading every book in my collection. He has become as ravenous in the pursuit of knowledge as his appetite for food.<br><br><b><i>7 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>It's amazing. In the span of a day, Testa has read every book in my extensive collection – and managed to somehow store that vast repertoire in his mind. I've quizzed him on a few subjects and it's amazing. He has full recall and an amazing insight into the subjects he's studied. He's now in the process of assimilating my research notes and log entries with regards to our T-Energy experiments.<br><br><b><i>8 Yal 4158</i></b><br><br>Testa has completed reading my notes and has made a few suggestions on how to make the process more efficient. His suggestions have been forwarded to the construction team in the Dwarven region. He's also come up with a possible reason as to why Algernon, Ben and the dog met their demise. It would seem that the T-Energy infusion (as we've done it thus far) didn't entirely replace the being's normal tissues. The T-Energy ate away at the tissues – all while stimulating its life force. But overall, the damage was far greater than the regenerative properties and when there was nothing left of the tissues – boom!<br><br>He suggested a tonic of his own creation that could better sustain his and any other subject's tissues to keep himself and anyone else we subject to this treatment a longer life after the infusion. There's one disturbng issue -  Testa suggests there's someone malignant corrupting our work. Strange.<br><br>In the meantime, the Sakkarim's remains seem to have cooled off enough to approach it. The invader appears to be made of rock. There's not much that can be gleaned from the remains. Whatever was inside the creature is now a mass of solid rock.<br><br><b><i>4 Nosk 4158</i></b><br><br>Testa, our first creation is still amongst the living. He's been alive for 28 days post infusion. The last few weeks have been a bit of a blur to the point where I haven't had so much as a moment to collect my thoughts, let alone commit them to the log. Construction in the new facility is coming along nicely.<br><br>Testa, in the meanwhile, has been busy. In addition to his research with us, he's been called away numerous times to deal with our uninvited guests. Good thing he doesn't seem to need any sleep. His appetite, on the other hand is simply astonishing. He eats enough food per day to feed a medium sized army. Good thing the military and the Seraphim are happy to contribute to his grocery list.<br><br>We seem to have hit a snag in our experimental progress. By Testa's calculations, there isn't enough naturally occurring free T-Energy in the east Bluestone Lake area to transform more than one or two more subjects. My analysis confirms his estimates. Unfortunately, we need far more than three of our creations to deal with the hundreds of invaders that have come through the portal.<br><br>We've also had a bit of an invasion of what can best be called the 'undead'. We've occasionally had problems with corpses buried too close to T-Energy pools coming back to what can be called "unlife". The appearance of the invaders, specifically the energy given off by Sakkarim seems to have reacted with T-Energy naturally occurring in graveyards and has brought skeletons back from the great beyond.<br><br>Meanwhile, we've heard the tale that the Dwarves are working on something that will close the portal in the Southern Desert permanently. We wish them luck. Anything that will stem the tide of the invasion is welcome news.<br><br><b><i>5 Nosk 4158</i></b><br><br>Testa has come up with a solution for our T-Energy shortfall. He's come up with a way to extract pure T-Energy from the land itself. The designs for the T-Energy siphons have been forwarded to the appropriate artisans have been given plans and teams of plumbers have been assembled to build a network of pipes across the face of the central continent that lead to our lab in the Dwarven region.<br><br>In the meantime, Testa has also requested a few of the dogs we had lined up for our previous tests and some materials to be delivered to him and some laboratory space. He said he had a spark of inspiration. I wonder just what he has in mind.<br><br><b><i>17 Nosk 4158</i></b><br><br>The first few siphons have been put into place and the pipeline that will feed our new facility will be ready by the end of the year. I only hope that we survive long enough to implement this grand plan. We will be leaving for the new facility tomorrow.<br><br><b><i>2 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>Our move is finally complete. Whoever said moving was fun, never had to move a staff of thirty, their books, notes, assorted lab implements, beakers, test tubes, and the other things that make our work possible. Fortunately, there's a portal near our destination.<br><br>The new complex is amazing. It spans several levels with all manner of controls for filling and maintaining the flow of T-Energy into the main reservoir. Speaking of which, the reservoir is an incredible sight to behold. It's HUGE!<br><br>Meanwhile, Testa's latest creation was finally revealed to the rest of us. He called them Guardians. They appear to fit the standard vitruvian model, two arms, legs, standing upright; however, they appear to have the head of a dog. These new guardians will be in charge of security of our new facility. Apparently, they are the product of Testa's experiments on the dogs. According to our giant blue friend, they will be fiercely loyal to the cause and will defend our new facility far better than any mere mortal can. Their artificial bodies combined with the fierce loyalty of their origins will see to that. Keriana's opposed to the idea, however. She says the Guardians will be cowardly and unstable, citing our dog infusion failures.<br><br><b><i>3 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>Our second and third test subjects have arrived. They've been briefed on the procedure and what to expect. They're both in agreement with everything and have signed documents to that effect. The T-Energy reservoir in the center of the new infuser is nearly full and the secondary reservoir that feeds into it is catching the overflow.<br><br>The first of our second batch of subjects is male and his records show that he's been a naughty boy. He was first a convicted killer in civilian life who was sentenced to life in the military. I suppose the powers that be felt his talents would best be served being channeled into something more productive. It also seems he went berserk and killed several of his comrades one night in a drunken brawl. He was to be executed for his treasonous acts and would have been had it not been for our little program. Sounds like a perfect addition to our forces.<br><br>The second subject is female. She is not, however, a convict. She is actually a volunteer to the program. Her records say she's a Dryad healer and philosopher who decided to enlist after her home was invaded by our unwelcome guests. There's something in there about her tribe being wiped out by a nasty dragon. No matter. Anyone bent on revenge is fine by me.<br><br><b><i>4 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>Testa briefly stopped by to inspect the volunteers before they were infused. He's given his nod of approval to both.<br><br>The male went into the new infusion chamber and the switch was flipped. A beam shot from the reservoir and hit him square in the chest. The reservoir was nearly fully drained before it stopped. The infusion appears to have been successful.<br><br>After a few hours, the reservoir was refilled from the storage tank inside the mountain to the east and the female stepped inside the chamber. She was amazingly calm and collected for someone about to undergo the transformation.<br><br>After the two had a chance to rest a bit and feast (in much the way Testa did when he was transformed), Testa himself went in to greet his new siblings. They introduced themselves as Kuan and Kybele.<br><br><b><i>5 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>The siphon network and the pipes leading to our facility are now complete. We are now able to refill the storage reservoir and the infusion reservoir in a matter of a few hours. With enough volunteers, we can create a rather substantial army of gifted warriors to fight for the cause.<br><br>The fourth and fifth test subjects arrived today. It seems the general populace has been given an opportunity to sign up for transformation. The military had run short of people they could spare. Testa has looked them over as well and has given his approval to both.<br><br>The male volunteer is a priest of the Church of the Creator who lost his entire congregation to an attack by what he called the "devil himself". The female is a High Elf. Her records show she spent the last few years in the university at Thylysium and she studied philosophy. Her reason for enlistment – it was only logical to do something to save the world.<br><br>Meanwhile Kuan and Kybele have both been dispatched to areas in the most need of their enhanced services. I'm not entirely certain how useful Kuan will turn out to be. His special talent involves a rather intoxicating breath that causes those who catch a whiff of it to go insane and attack anything and everything that moves – friend or foe.<br><br>Kybele's talent, on the other hand is a bright light that heals the injured (on our side) and reinforces them to carry on the attack. It would seem she is best suited to follow in Kuan's footsteps, repairing our forces that were cut down by his bad breath.<br><br><b><i>6 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>With the reservoir now fully restocked, we were able to proceed with our fourth and fifth test subjects. Since we couldn't figure out which one should go first, we flipped a coin, an Ancarian 50 Goldpiece. The girl won the toss.<br><br>She stepped into the chamber and the switch was pulled. Her body was flooded with T-Energy just like Kuan and Kybele had been. Success! Her transfiguration went without a hitch. Again, a few hours later, the male stepped inside the chamber after the reservoir was refilled and he was likewise transformed.<br><br>The new female warrior now calls herself Forens and the male calls himself Lumen. Forens' gift is quite useful. She can cause attacks made by the invaders to be reflected back at them. As long as she keeps her concentration up, she can reflect damage back until the enemy has destroyed themselves.<br><br>Lumen's talent is quite impressive as well. He can cause his body to glow incredibly brightly. The light, when it hits one of the invaders, causes it to burst into flames. The only thing left of one of those Sakkarim is a pile of molten slag. Dragons, on the other hand, wind up being a pile of charred bones and ash.<br><br>They, like their siblings, have ravenous appetites as well. I must remember to expand the grocery requsition immediately!<br><br><b><i>25 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>This may well be my final entry. The invaders aren't nearly as stupid as they seem. They've organized a well thought out attack strategy that called our team of five enhanced beings away from the facility to far remote places where they couldn't easily get back. In the meantime an attack force of at least ten dragons and Sakkarim came knocking on our front door. The outer defensive fortresses have slowed their advance enough for us take measures. We've sealed the outer door and have activated the fail-safe mechanism Testa came up with. It's quite brilliant, really. It infuses four common Ancarian fleas into huge battle ready monsters. Should those Sakkarim make it to the infusion chamber, they're in for a very, very nasty surprise. I wish I had thought of that little trick myself.<br><br>We've sent a message to our five gifted warriors, but I fear they may not return in time. I must now activate the Guardians. This will take some time before they're fully operational.<br><br><b><i>25 Valka 4158</i></b><br><br>(later) It seems this will be my final entry, after all. Keriana has suddenly decided to show her true colors. Turns out, she was plotting to supplant me for some time and it was she, who's tried to engineer my downfall by a memo to the Unification Council, citing unethical experimentation on sentients. She's been stealing material, including dragon DNA samples. How blind I've been!<br><br>So then, she made her way to the infusion chamber and activated the procedure, before the security team I've sent managed to intercept her. The transformation was the most bizarre of the lot. Keriana appears to have merged with one of those Ancarian fleas. It would seem one of the fail-safe surprises jumped on her body and the two of them have somehow fused together. She now has SIX arms. Her first deed, once she emerged from the chamber was to attack the security team with some baleful energy, mutating them into something closely resembling the Sakkarim. With her new escort she has made her way to the main entry to the facility. The carnage that ensued was truly a hideous sight to behold. The remote viewers placed outside of the facility caught most of it. It was quite terrifying.<br><br>The aliens' strike force has been wiped out, she is now on her way back to the facility. The flying fish aliens and the ones with the skin made of hardened bone stand no chance against her. She will be here in a few minutes, I somehow hear her voice in my head now. She demands an unrestricted access to the infusion chamber! I've locked the doors again and reset the fail-safe device.<br><br>The outer door still holds. Me and what remains of the facility security have entrenched ourselves at the makeshift fortifications near the entry teleporter. I've sent the rest of my staff back to Ciria Delith by way of the portal along with my research notes and a model of the infuser. Perhaps someone can continue my work. Testa surely can. I hope that the people of Ancaria forgive us for the Chaos we've unleashed upon the world.<br><br>The Guardians are fully operational, and our "Magnificent Five" are approaching. My "dear" former chief assistant will not get her prize.<br><br>And to think I finally learned her new name just yesterday. Ker...
0848965269	Back again? Please, near the cave! Failitia is waiting!
0857402412	The village where I fought the elemental is to northeast of here, near the foot of the mountains. I think it lives up there in the clouds. Something must have drawn it down here to cause havoc.
0865007314	What the...! Is noone here what they seem to be?
0872985851	I thought that we had finished this task, but Lydia told me that the things we had done were only a temporary solution. We prevented the situation from getting worse, but the origin of the spider plague still remains inside the cave. Now I must return to the cave and finish what we have started...
0999662847	These guardians aren't looking very friendly. Nor do they look like they would be willing to talk. They want to do things the hard way.
1017835984	I have passed Monwarion's plans successfully. The man really enjoys a good reputation among the inquisitors.<br><br>Good to know that there are still members of the clergy who want to serve the people and stand up for their beliefs.
1027922558	I defeated the Lightning Lord. Tizz'Agoz must be eager to learn of my success.
1064641306	According to Toren's directions, the cave should be north of here.
1064641307	So this is the cave Toren was talking about. Might as well go inside and see if he was telling the truth.
1064641309	So these are the guardians... I wonder if they can be reasoned with. I will try talking to them first.
1073834395	You are welcome. I have heard a lot of your deeds. So I told Rinah to look for you.<br><br>As Rinah has already told you, the clergy has split into two groups. The group of Nimonuil has plunged into chaos with all their regime. Now they are fighting the high nobility to obtain the autocracy and underestimate beyond the threat of the T-energy, yes they even want to control and use it! The other group, which I am a member of, wants to restore the old unity between the nobility and clergy. We are of the opinion that the clergy should watch primarily on the needs of the people. But as long as Nimonuil is Grand Inquisitor, chances are very badly. However, I have a plan on how we can undermine his power.
1082757747	You have my thanks stranger.
1145724575	Well, Rinah has gone so back to her "regular seat". I'm going to talk to her. I like to hear what excuses she has.
1196515532	Meet Failitia.<br><br>This is truly horrible! First thing you should know is that Failitia has nothing to do with all these murders. She came to see me a short while ago. She told me about an evil force that goes by the same name. She makes no secret of that. At times it even seems she is purposely trying to slander Failitia's good name. Who knows, it might be someone whose path we crossed in our younger days. One thing is for certain... Failitia needs help! You can find her near the cave. She will know who you are! Go now, please!
1212614951	I met a lone Lizard warrior named Tizz'Agoz, who had recently battled a lightning elemental nearby. Apparently his quarry was more than he could handle, and he had to retreat to the ruins here to lick his wounds. I've agreed to fight this lightning elemental, in exchange for a substantial cut of the bounty as payment.
1242876214	Essence of Dark Matters
1242953509	Bringer of Light
1242953510	Power of NIF
1244344880	Endijian's Bulwark
1245812971	The Scythe of the Slayer
1245812972	Helmet of Unspeakable Evil
1245812973	A Northland Tale
1245812974	Austerness
1245812975	Fairness
1245812976	Steadfastness
1245812977	Protective Hands
1245812978	Resilience
1245812979	Sense of Duty
1245812980	Dedication
1245813084	Honor
1245813085	Holy Wrath
1245813086	Patience of Saints
1245813087	True Faith
1245813202	Starlight
1245813203	Eternal Breeze
1245813204	Pulse of Time
1245813205	Creators Legacy
1245813206	Breath of the Firmament
1245813310	Striders of Aeons
1245813311	Pillars of Millenia
1245813312	Sash of Infinity
1245813313	Bearer of Light
1245813425	Helmet of Avernus
1245813426	Breastplate of Dis
1245813427	Belt of Minauros
1245813428	Bracers of Phlegethos
1245813429	Gloves of Stygia
1245813430	Boots of Malbolge
1245813431	Legplates of Baalzebul
1245813432	Ring of Cania
1245813536	Ring of Nessus
1245813538	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 2
1245813539	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 3
1245813540	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 4
1245813541	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 5
1245813542	Journal of Aesma Daeva, Part 1
1245813544	Yersinia Pestis
1245813545	Rapid Decimation
1245813649	Cold War
1245813650	Complete Subjugation
1245813651	Reckless Conquest
1245813652	Longtime Famine
1245813653	Cloak of Death
1245813654	Pure Despair
1245813655	Icy Lament
1245813656	A Sword of Light and Darkness
1245813657	The Redeemer
1245813658	Forest's Legacy
1245813762	Tree Spirit's Secret
1245813763	Forest Guardian's Protector
1245813764	Al
1245813765	Ata
1245813766	Atu
1245813767	Ber
1245813768	Dai
1245813769	Del
1245813770	Dis
1245813771	Em
1245813875	Im
1245813876	Ith
1245813877	Kilth
1245813878	Kla
1245813879	Luv
1245813880	Mar
1245813881	Mor
1245813882	Nik
1245813883	Ory
1245813884	Payn
1245813988	Sin
1245813989	Tel
1245813990	Ter
1245813991	Tom
1245813992	Truk
1245813993	Tuh
1245813994	Ver
1245813995	Vun
1245813996	Wol
1245813997	Xion
1245825740	Yer
1245825741	Twinkle
1245825742	Icingdeath
1245825743	Mielikki's Grace
1245825744	Guenhwyvar's Refuge
1245825745	Spider's Bane
1245825747	Light of Eärendil
1245825857	Divine Spark
1245825859	Vessel of Chaos
1245825860	Dawn of Scheherazade
1245825861	Cradle of Light
1245825862	BLUEPRINT_3519
1245825966	Fusion Igniters
1245825967	Dark Matter Conduits
1245825968	BLUEPRINT_3522
1245825969	Star Meadows
1245825970	BLUEPRINT_3524
1245826080	Trinity's Kicks
1245826081	Trickery Slacks
1245826082	Coat of Arms
1245826083	Trinity's Cage
1245826084	Evasion Cuffs
1245826085	Firecrackers
1245826086	Trinity's High Hat
1245851278	The Dark Side
1245851279	Windu's Mace
1245851280	Disturbance in the Force
1245851281	Light Source
1245851282	Maul's Swordstaff
1245851393	Fleeting Moment
1245851394	Wisdom of the Dragons
1245851395	Guardian's Word
1245851396	Shaman's Mask
1245851397	Hunting Instinct
1245851399	King of Beasts
1245864047	Flame Dragon
1245864048	Rime Dragon
1245864049	Oracle Dragon
1245864050	Wild Dragon
1245864051	Watchdog Mobiculum
1245864052	Atomic Mobiculum
1245864053	Energy Core Mobiculum
1245864054	Skirmish Mobiculum
1245864055	Volcanic Tiger
1245864056	Genesis Tiger
1245864160	Mystique Tiger
1245864161	Irrepressible Tiger
1245864162	Enforcer Hound
1245864163	Colossus Hound
1245864164	Crypt Hound
1245864165	Hound of Havoc
1245864166	Infernal Draconicon
1245864167	Elemental Draconicon
1245864168	Ethereal Draconicon
1245864169	Savage Draconicon
1245864273	Blight Spider
1245864274	Apocalypse Spider
1245864275	Scourge Spider
1245864276	Fiend Spider
1245864277	Voracious Lizard
1245864278	Chthonic Lizard
1245864279	Hex Lizard
1245864280	Indomitable Lizard
1245864281	Hippocampus
1245864282	Aureus Drake
1245864386	Argenteus Drake
1247204800	Jörmungandr's Venom
1247204801	Hydra's Regeneration
1247204905	Lotan's Unbreakable Skull
1247204906	Fafnir's Burning Blood
1247204907	Illuyanka's Guile
1247204908	Ladon's Vigilance
1247204909	Leviathan's Hardened Scales
1247204910	Vritra's Tenacity
1247204911	Shesha's Paean
1247204912	Mizuchi's Deep Waters
1247204913	Kaliya's Promise
1247204914	Mei Long's Slumber
1247205018	Druk's Thunder
1247205019	Qing Long's Everlasting Spring
1247205020	Watatsumi's Protection
1247205021	Bashe's Voracity
1247205022	Ouroboros' Advent
1247205023	Apep's Eclipse
1247205024	Nosferatu Fang
1247205025	Lycanthrope Claw
1247205026	Dreadjudge Bracers
1247205027	Shadowbender Boots
1247205131	Gorestone Plate
1247205132	Plaguewrath Gauntlets
1247205133	Deathshade Helm
1247205134	Windhowler Greaves
1247205135	Blackjade Belt
1247205136	Blightfire Pauldrons
1247205137	Scarred Soul
1247205138	Bloodmoon Visor
1247205139	Irresistable Calling
1247205140	Gates of Sheogh
1247205244	Dark Heir
1247205245	Rage of Urgash
1247205246	Traitor's Brand
1247205247	Hellcaller's Inferno
1247205248	Aeon Flux
1247205249	Shield of the Cid
1247205250	Thylysian Galea
1247205251	Breastplate of Expansion
1247205252	Malassa's Secret
1247205253	Ylath's Scrutiny
1247205357	Sar-Elam's Oblation
1247205358	Arkath's Vehemence
1247205359	Elrath's Luminosity
1247205360	Sylanna's Contemplation
1247205361	Shalassa's Sagacity
1247205362	Transfixion Orb
1247205363	Firebird's Wing
1247205364	Ostur's Shredder
1247205365	Celioth's Ward
1247205366	Dralkcib's Protection
1247205470	Shield of the Dark Crusade
1247205471	Kufferath Defender
1247205472	Khorum Reflector
1247205473	Swampshield of the Leech
1247205474	Hellknight's Shield
1247205475	Hellknight's Blade
1247205476	Labrys the Star-Axe
1247205477	Aestus Obscura
1247205478	Dracunculus Pipe
1247205479	Quetzalcoatl's Breath
1247205583	Sylvanwood Bow
1247205584	Spinebender Bow
1247205585	Bone of Ullr
1247205586	Skeleton Key
1247205587	Snickersnee
1247205588	Noisy Cricket
1247205589	Kaleidoscopic Evangelist
1247205590	Electric Executioner
1247205591	Waton's Dreamblade
1247205592	Halberd of the Rocks
1247205696	Longinus Lance
1247205697	Wand of Abaris
1247205698	Snowstaff of the Ogre
1247205699	Twilight Harvester
1247205700	Wyvern Charmer
1247205701	Staff of the Blood Dryads
1247205702	Serpent's Gaze
1247205703	The Lost
1247205704	Shaman's Totem
1247205705	The Withered
1247205809	Wayfarer's Staff
1247205810	Delior's Holy Staff
1247205811	Agh'Ba's Dreadful Staff of Death
1247205812	Frost Weaver's Elemental Staff
1247205813	Troll Carver
1247205814	Molotov Cocktail
1247205815	Windbiter
1247205816	Star of Astaroth
1247205818	Jedi Mind Trick
1247217561	Sceptrum Dominus
1247217562	Globus Cruciger
1247217563	Vox Principis
1247217564	Pugno Tyrannus
1247217565	Ghoul Blade
1247217566	Tomahawk of the Wendigo
1247217567	Tengu's Ambush
1247217568	Jotun's Maw
1247217569	Eugene's Axe
1247217570	Horns of the Forest God
1247217674	The Herald
1247217675	The Seeker
1247217676	Sereish Steel of Thunder
1247217677	To Mega Therion
1247217678	Laurelinad's Agonizer
1247217679	Bartuc's Cutthroat
1247217680	The Night
1247217681	The Silent Water
1247217682	Left Eye of Glaurung
1247217683	Right Eye of Glaurung
1247217787	Ring of Talons
1247217788	Ring of Heartscales
1247217789	Ring of Tail Spikes
1247217790	Glaurung's Head
1247217791	Trang-Oul's Guise
1247217792	Blessed Reliquary
1247217793	Heathen Inferno
1247217794	Searing Deliverance
1247217795	Unrelenting Assault
1247217796	Pagan Damnation
1247217900	War Striders
1247217901	Wrath Channelers
1247217902	Colossal of Menoth
1247217903	Kingu's Bleeding Wound
1247217904	Lucifer's Plummet
1247217905	Iblis' Stiffened Spine
1247217906	Belial's Broken Idol
1247217907	Phaëton's Precarious Grip
1247217908	Hephaestus' Limp
1247217909	Anzu's Shattered Wings
1247218013	Attar's Uncertain Rule
1247218014	Parabellum
1247218015	Dyria's Canopy
1247218016	Desert Rose
1247218017	Magol En Agar
1247218018	Heridon's Jade Saber
1247218019	Phantasm
1247218020	Bone Blade of Zhurag-Nar
1247218021	Astral Longsword of Warlocks
1247218022	Amazonian Aegis
1247218126	Mirror Shades
1247218127	Tactical T-Shirt
1247218128	Denim Shorts
1247218129	Skinny Jeans
1247218130	External Memory
1247218131	TickTacks
1247218132	Track Mitts
1247218133	The Arbiter
1247218134	The Osiris Scythe
1247218135	Parashu
1247218240	Sophia's Flight
1247218241	Sophia's Chastity
1247218242	Sophia's Endowment
1247218243	Sophia's Footstep
1247218244	Sophia's Passion
1247218245	Sophia's Discipline
1247218246	Sophia's Foresight
1247218247	Sophia's Vigor
1247218248	Osseous Bulwark
1247218352	Decayer's Brand
1247218353	Sanguine Runeblade
1247218354	Amulet of Discord
1247218355	Djed Amulet
1247218356	Sword of Rebellion
1247218357	Clouded Mirror
1247218358	Cooling Crystal
1247218359	Unbreakable Diamond
1247218360	Lazulite of Clarity
1247218361	Mystic Sapphire
1247218465	Blue Carbuncle
1247218466	Aquamarine of Fortitude
1247218467	Glory of the Dawn
1247218468	Silence of Midnight
1247218469	Light of Day
1247218470	Height of Noon
1247218471	The Darkest Hour
1247218472	Colors of Sunset
1247218473	Mystery of the Night
1247218474	Jaguar's Bite
1247218578	Lion's Mane
1247218579	Lynx's Thick Fur
1247218580	Cougar's Paws
1247218581	Leopard's Agility
1247218582	Cheetah's Sprint
1247218583	Tiger's Tail
1247218584	Barthus' Disdain
1247218585	Orphas' Charge
1247218586	Fangil's Demise
1247218587	Nimble's Magic Eye
1247230330	Varmin's Gambit
1247230331	Gemblik's Envy
1247230332	Sage Njari's Cipher
1247230333	Mer-Kil's Stratagem
1247230334	Smoking Demon
1247230335	Sneaking Demon
1247230337	Torch of Light
1247230338	Axe-Bot 2525
1247230339	Forgotten Technology
1247230443	Spear of the Dryads
1247230444	Carnach's Scorching Stake
1247230445	Stormcrow's Hat
1247230446	Sudden Fury
1247230447	The Catalyst
1247230448	Charge Integrator
1247230449	The Iron Knight
1247230450	Helm of the Einherjar
1247230451	The Nemes Headgear
1247230452	Valkyrie's Profile
1247230556	The Earth-Shaker
1247230557	Soulflay Fork
1247230558	Father's Sword
1247230559	Danse Macabre
1247230560	Inner Demon
1247243440	Mystic Pearl
1247243441	Pestilent Fang
1247243442	Inferno Rock
1247243443	Arctic Crystal
1247255989	Ogre Knuckle
1247255990	Rainbow Facet
1247256094	Ogre Knuckle
1247256779	Plow
1324483648	Ah! It is starting to make sense. There are TWO Failitia's, the Seraphim being one, and the other being her evil counterpart. Sounds as if this evil twin is causing all the trouble. I am to contact Failitia the Seraphim near a cave.
1360032363	The Lightning Lord
1392336419	Lydia was happy to hear about the victory. She even wanted to order a sculptor to make a statue, so that my victory would be set in stone. The reward was very generous as well. Though this assignment was dangerous I am glad now to have accepted and accomplished it.
1420171122	I have the three plows and now I have to take them to the armorer. Good grief, these things are heavy!
1504109656	I should go to a few representatives of the Inquisition and transmit Monwarions instructions to them.<br><br>The first would be the guard on duty officer in the central prison of Thylysium. Then there are Commander Amalia in the camp near Twainbrook and Tahlreth, the competent Inquisitor of Sloeford on my list.
1530812044	Well, I will prepare the other guards step by step. Despite everything, I can not let you pass unfortunately. If you're seen passing here by someone, Master Monwarions plans could be at risk, not to mention your safety. You will have to look for another way, friend. Bon Voyage and good luck.
1604863515	An armorer has asked me to steal three plows from nearby farms so that he can use the metal to forge some weapons. It sounds easy enough.
1645770036	I am glad this is over, it is all getting quite bothersome! Failitia was overjoyed. Something about light triumphing, I couldn't care less!
1752280927	Plowshares to Swords
1808365963	Visit Na'Fian and find Seriefa.<br><br>Unfortunately I cannot really tell you more. It's vague rumours at the very least. Nonetheless... I am concerned. Failitia was one of my dearest friends. She was a true force to be reckoned with when trouble came. Aahh, the stories I could tell you about those days! But... that is not what you are here for. I suggest seeking out Seriefa. I do know that she and Failitia remained close friends when we parted. Last I know is that she lived near Na'Fian. I really hope you can put an end to this mess, Failitia does not deserve this slander! This cannot be her!
1873118855	Bring me three plows!<br><br>Come closer my friend - take a look around! I know, it's not exactly a magnificent forge. I simply can't find enough metal these days! The price of metal has risen astronomically since one of the southern mines collapsed. It's an absolute disaster - and just when the clone, er sorry, clan wars are escalating. I could make a real killing on the market, if only I could get my hands on some metal! Well, what do you think? There are plenty of farmers hereabouts, are you clever enough to steal a plow or two? Three should be enough for now.
1924667134	Who is who?
2000732001	The Mutated Dragon has been killed. I should get back to the priest now. I know he's anxiously awaiting the news.
2022479290	<b><i>5 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>We've managed to appropriate a larger laboratory, thanks to the flame-haired assistant of mine. Turns out her name is Keriana, she is of the House Worganar, those guys pretty much control the Elven Senate. Good to have her in the team. We've now got a larger vat and a bigger supply of T-Energy to work with. We've also gotten some dire stray dogs to experiment with, the Animal Protection Society should be of no trouble, not with the political cover we now have. We will begin tests as soon as the lab is ready. Should make sure the power surge required to make the experiment work is set correctly.<br><br><b><i>6 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>We had some disturbing news from the old lab. Apparently, Algernon didn't come out for its daily feed today. Ben was quite happy to shadow step its way out of its cage and devoured its portion and half of Algernon's plate. Algernon was showing some signs of being a bit listless in its cage.<br><br><b><i>7 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>We're ready to try our next experiment. The vat is filled; our first dog is about as ready as he will ever be. The power settings appear to be approximately what was running through the vat in the old lab.<br><br><b><i>8 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>We conducted our first dog based T-Energy test today. It was less than a raving success. What was once a mean spirited nearly feral dog became almost timid after infusion. I have no idea why. Apparently, personality has something to do with it. More experimentation will need to be done.<br><br><b><i>9 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>Disaster! We got a report from our old lab. Algernon exploded. The people monitoring the two mutant rats reported that Algernon hadn't eaten anything for 4 days – and that it had started glowing a brighter shade of blue just before it happened. They also reported a few minutes before Algernon exploded, Ben had shadow stepped out from its confines and fled the lab. Somehow, it knew what was going to happen before it did. Ben had vanished and hasn't been seen since. Algernon survived for all of 24 days. Not as promising as we once imagined, however, we'll have to see what our current test subjects have to offer.<br><br><b><i>10 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>The explosion in our former quarters has caught the attention of the powers that be in Ciria Delith. They have requested that we find a more appropriate location for our experiments. Requests made to the various regions of Ancaria have come up short. The common theme for the rejection was the same –<b><i>Not</i></b> in my back yard! Bah! Bureaucrats! Technophobes! How are we supposed to save the world from the invaders without taking bold steps? Surely, some losses on our side must be acceptable. Nothing ventured, nothing gained.<br><br>The Dwarves finally agreed to allow us to build a facility in the southern portion of their domain on the western side of the central continent. It's a mountainous region riddled with caves and canyons. They felt that the surrounding mountains would contain most any explosions so they wouldn't harm the rest of Ancaria. Unfortunately the area is devoid of T-Energy so we will need to figure out some means to import it from other parts of the continent.<br><br>In the mean time, our T-Energy dog really hasn't worked out very well. It hasn't eaten since his transfiguration. It hasn't so much as displayed any interesting talents gained from the infusion. In fact, it hasn't done anything except cower in complete fear in its kennel. What a disappointment. We fear its end is near.<br><br><b><i>13 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>The T-Energy dog exploded today. Fortunately, this time we were somewhat prepared. We put it in a boat and towed it far out to sea. The explosion was immense. We calculated it was roughly four times larger than the one caused by Algernon. Given the dog was proportionally four times larger, this fits in nicely. No damage was done – except for the boat the dog and its kennel were on. Too bad we couldn't include a few of the invaders. I doubt, however, they would have been willing to cooperate.<br><br>Given the failure of our one canine subject, we need to find another species to experiment on. One that can be controlled and be made to attack the invaders. It's not like we have forever to deal with the current problem. Our astronomers at the Celestial Dome have concluded that our world, Ancaria, will be passing close to and possibly coming into contact with the dimensional rift caused by those idiot Orcs and their accursed portal accident – again. Who knows how many invaders will be coming through the portal this time around. The forecast is not a good one.<br><br><b><i>18 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>We've received a report from near Orcish Byway about a medium sized explosion near the town. It appears Ben had just about made it to Nor Plat before its time ran out. Not too surprising given that Ben and all of our test rats were obtained from Orcish traders from Karagh.<br><br><b><i>21 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>Construction on the new site for our laboratory is progressing very nicely. Once again, my chief assistant's talents and connections have proven invaluable. Due to her, the facility will be guarded by not one, but three fortresses, so security shouldn't be much of an issue.<br><br>We still need test subjects for our experiments. It seems none of Ancaria's fauna would be compatible with the goals of our experiments.<br><br><b><i>23 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>Keriana and I had a bit of a brainstorm last night. I sent a note to the local prison warden to see, if he had any prisoners scheduled for execution. If the transformation is a death sentence, it really doesn't matter how soon they cease to exist. Or for that matter, how they cease to exist. And who knows, they may, in fact, find some measure of redemption should our experiments succeed.<br><br><b><i>26 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>Bloody bureaucrats! The powers that be got wind of my request. I can only wonder, who's spilled the beans... I've been called before the full Ancarian Unification Council to explain my request. I report to them tomorrow morning.<br><br><b><i>27 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>Disaster! My appearance before the council was postponed. It would seem Ancaria not only came into contact with the rift but collided with it head on. It was also about a fortnight ahead of schedule.<br><br>What emerged from the portal this time around was truly the stuff of nightmares. The invaders we've had to deal with the first time around were nothing in comparison to what emerged in the past few hours. Huge winged monsters, bigger than a two story noble's house that exhale fire! Other huge winged monstrosities that seem to be burning from within. They can scoop up huge chunks of dirt and melt them in their hands. This is NOT good. We aren't ready yet. This is NOT good.<br><br><b><i>28 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>The new invaders have spread far and wide. The huge flying lizards that exhale fire number in the hundreds. They appear to be giant dragons – the kind that hasn't been seen on Ancaria for a thousand generations. The sort of dragons you can find on Ancaria in this day and age are nowhere near the purported size being reported. They're maybe twice the size of a normal riding horse with a wing-spread about twice as long.<br><br><b><i>28 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>(later) We've just received a report from a brave soul willing to go to the eastern portion of the southern desert on the eastern continent where the portal came into contact with Ancaria. The portal now seems to be firmly locked onto the spot where it landed. This time it's not going away. Crap.
2092694257	<b><i>4 Abrill 4157</i></b><br><br>The project, that I've been assigned to supervise on behalf of the Ancarian Unification Council, is progressing nicely. Today should be a big day. Fergorn and Liebo will be doing their first tests on their new portal today. This should be quite spectacular – nearly instantaneous travel to any part of Ancaria. Just tell the portal where you want to go and you can be there in the time it takes to blink twice. The distance doesn't matter – 5 kiloms or 5000 – you're simply there.<br><br>It will certainly make things much easier to get around and with a little luck, finally bring about peace between all the races of Ancaria. No one can invade another's territory when the response would come quickly and without mercy from a crack squad of Seraphim Guardians.<br><br>It really is amazing what can be accomplished when the races of Ancaria work together instead of all the senseless fighting. Fergorn, the Dwarven smith and Liebo the Elvish scientist really have put their heads together and come up with something quite spectacular!<br><br><b><i>5 Abrill 4157</i></b><br><br>The first test went off without any complications. The portal in Ciria Delith was stable for several hours. On the next test, a volunteer will be stepping through the portal to see where if it's stable enough to go beyond the Central continent. If all goes well, it will deposit the volunteer on the Far Eastern continent of Ancaria, at the Tyr-Hadar outpost.<br><br><b><i>7 Abrill 4157</i></b><br><br>Disaster! Fergorn and Liebo made a slight miscalculation in the location of the portal's exit. Instead of depositing Sargol, the volunteer, neatly through the target arch in Tyr-Hadar, he emerged from the portal at a rather great height – and the resulting fall broke most of poor Sargol's bones. He did not survive. Oh well, back to the drawing board...<br><br><b><i>16 Abrill 4157</i></b><br><br>Finally! Success! Instead of risking any live volunteers, the portal team decided it was better to send a small device through, complete with a communications crystal tuned to a receiver here in Ciria Delith. The device arrived intact, exactly where it was supposed to show up. The commander of the Tyr-Hadar outpost reported back with the good news by way of the device.<br><br><b><i>31 Abrill 4157</i></b><br><br>The Ancarian Unification Council came to inspect the portals. Fergorn and Liebo's portal demonstration for them worked flawlessly as it has for the past few weeks and construction will begin immediately.<br><br><b><i>22 Samar 4157</i></b><br><br>The Orcish delegation is complaining that their portals are taking a very long time to build. They're accusing Fergorn and Liebo of taking their sweet time in getting the ones in Ruka and Entruag installed. They couldn't seem to understand that it takes time to find the right kind of stone to build portals and that those stones must be cut precisely and the runes had to be engraved properly. And that any deviation from doing things right would result in accidents – like the one that killed poor Sargol. Precision work can NOT be rushed! And furthermore, the stones can not be shipped by way of portal to any destination. The feedback from the stones passing through the field would cause an implosion the likes of which has never been seen on Ancaria.<br><br>But they are Orcs after all, and they aren't all that intelligent. They have been arguing that a few accidents here and there were acceptable losses. Orcs! They are very difficult to reason with.<br><br><b><i>27 Samar 4157</i></b><br><br>Unbelievable! The Orcs claim to have built a portal of their own. They just couldn't wait three months for the installation team to get to Nor Plat and install the portals. A Dwarven inspection team was dispatched to check into it from Gildstadt in the western provinces. They, of course, did not take any chances and arrived at the Grunwald portal and walked the rest of the way.<br><br><b><i>4 Gindar 4157</i></b><br><br>The inspection team reported in today. While the stones seem to be the right sort of material, they were found to be substandard grade. The Orcs were of course, incensed. Fortunately, Hargol, one of Fergorn and Liebo's most trusted assistants was at hand. When the Orcs tried to activate their inferior portal, he was able to channel the overload of energy into the heavens. The resulting explosion lit up the night sky for three days and nights. The Orcs were, for the moment, suitably impressed and agreed to dismantle their inferior portal and be patient.<br><br><b><i>7 Gindar 4157</i></b><br><br>Hargol's report has some members of the Ancarian Unification Council upset. As there are no Orcs on Fergorn and Liebo's research team, the question was raised as to how the Orcs were able to arrive at a portal design that was almost identical to the one the design team came up with.<br><br>The Dwarves and Elves were upset because they felt there must have been some industrial espionage being done by the Orcs or someone in their employ. No one can come up with a device that is such a nearly perfect copy without having seen the original. Coincidence only goes just so far before credibility is stretched beyond reason. The Humans are upset because if war broke out between the Orcs, Dwarves and Elves, it would likely mean their lands would be the center of the battle as their territory inconveniently borders all three race's homelands in their Grunwald region. The Seraphim weren't exactly happy either - after all their hard work building up the Ancarian Unification Council. All of the potential for peace lost because of one party's impatience.<br><br>The Lizardmen were about the only ones who could seemingly care less as they had no stake in any of this.
2185424394	I stumbled upon a most isolated temple in the Jungle region. The caretaker there seems to have a problem with one of his former pet dragons that became a T-Mutant. I agreed to destroy the Dragon, and in exchange the priest will trade with me from his stock of elite mounts.
2292740822	Kill the Mutated Dragon!<br><br>Greetings traveler. I am a humble priest, destined to serve the Gods in a remote location. I stay in this half-forgotten temple and rarely see anyone, except for hunters and travelling merchants who stop once in a while to make offerings to the Gods. I spend my free time breeding and training exotic creatures. Those rare times when I do leave the temple, my pets usually follow me. I think that animals make good companions to lone travelers like me... and like you. We may be able to come to an arrangement.<br><br>You see, while returning from my yearly pilgramage to the Sea of Heavens, one of my pet dragons wandered off the path into a dreadful mire of T-Energy. He was... changed. This mutated monster is no longer the pet I once knew and loved. He's a danger to the world. If you can help me by destroying it, I would be most grateful. You will be allowed to purchase some my most elite and highly specialized mounts to accompany you on your journeys. Do you accept?
2332841806	Elite Mounts
2420216394	Find Turok, the Ork in the jungle.<br><br>Greetings young adventurer! And good fortune that we meet this day, for I have an urgent request. Please stay awhile and listen. Recently I have heard some unsettling news. Turok, one of my oldest friends came to see me. It seems our mutual friend Failitia is in some sort of serious trouble! Disappearances... Abduction... even murder! I cannot believe this... there is no way she is capable of such horrors! Please, contact Turok, he will surely be able to tell you more.
2431869599	Turok seemed really concerned. Maybe this is worth the investigation after all. Failitia, as I now know, is a Seraphim, and cannot be the reason of all this commotion. At least, that is what her friends are convinced of. Turok sent me off to Na'Fian, where Seriefa should be able to enlighten me.
2512907104	Hurry up! I'm never going to be able make enough swords without the metal from those plows!<br>You're not having second thoughts are you? They're just farmers, who cares about them?
2521234428	Plow
2521234532	Plow
2532635995	The Root of all Evil
2640419455	The T-Energy Field is north of the desert, just past the Bengaresh Threshold. You may have to venture deep in the northeast part of the corruption in order to track him down. I dread to think how much he may have changed since I last saw him.
2693293500	Failitia's Seeker
2693293501	Failitia's Seeker
2693293722	MacLeod
2693293723	Ramirez
2693293724	Kurgan
2693293725	Kastagir
2693293726	Failitia's Seeker
2693293727	Failitia's Seeker
2694736619	Nemaya
2694736620	Turok
2694736621	Seriefa
2694736622	Failitia, Dreamweaver of the Gods
2694736623	Asmarael, the Queen of Spiders
2697622413	Failitia's Warrior
2697648067	mcgeitner
2697648290	Munera
2697648291	Kalia
2699040108	edladner
2700444361	desm
2700470126	Failitia's Warrior
2700470127	Failitia's Warrior
2700470128	Failitia's Warrior
2700470129	Failitia's Warrior
2700470130	Failitia's Warrior
2700495210	michme
2700495549	lostprophet
2701938897	marcuswob
2701938898	flix
2701938899	czevak
2701938900	Pesmontis
2701950768	Toren
2701951108	Slevin
2701989072	burn-x
2702002186	Prinz v.H.
2703330161	XiDragon
2703342586	LazyTomcat
2703343037	Wolfie2kX
2703343152	Dajan
2703355580	dimitrius154
2703368576	komissar_Mumm
2703420108	Failitia's Warrior
2703420109	Failitia's Warrior
2703444625	tomger
2704772829	Silver_fox
2704772833	kovu2296
2704773510	Bughunter
2704773622	Sir Quickly
2704810908	mapoalex
2704823677	Barristan
2704823902	RaveAir
2704823905	FTR
2704836895	Frank "Rente" Rentmeister
2704837125	davb37
2704837234	oOfilthOo
2704837235	Ice_Flame
2798474124	Lieutenant Rinah awaits you. Let's not bother her, she may otherwise be quite uncomfortable.
2940877153	Is it done...? What! You'd let this evil live and turn on me. I will stop you! You will not succeed!
2942761583	The Chief Inquisitor Monwarion has prepared a plan of how to weaken the Grand Inquisitor, so that he can be overthrown and the clergy can return to its old role again.
2987647771	I understand. Then I'll treat the prisoners now better than before until I get command to release them. And now move on before we're seen together!
2987647772	Excellent. If the Venerable Monwarion wants to lead negotiations with the high nobility, I will take no further action against their soldiers. Bon Voyage, dear adventurer.
2987647773	The Chief Inquisitor Monwarion was always a true idol for the Clergy. If he is planning such a measure, he has my trust and can count on my support.
3006565874	Yes? Nemaya sent you? This must be about Failitia, the Seraphim!
3012195843	I couldn't help overhearing - he was talking about the Great Machine, wasn't he? I know something about it!<br><br>I've seen it with my own eyes. You see, I come from Bluestonbury. You may have heard of it. It's in a cave north of town. But beware of the guardians. They're a nasty lot. I snuck in there once to see if they had any treasure. But they ran me off. Maybe you might have better luck...
3079779216	What the...! Is noone here what they seem to be?
3107000902	To walk two paths simultaneously, is to be ever grey, neither black nor white. Neither day or night. Walk on well, and with my thanks.
3115671570	You did it. I can't believe it! Have you seen the Great Machine?<br><br>What? It wasn't there? You are kidding, right?<br><br>Books? Only pieces of worthless paper. Keep them, I'm only interested in the Great Machine itself, not in another story about it. Bah!
3147206979	The blacksmith was very pleased. Now he can take up his trade again.
3147321328	Bugs!
3160619917	Hmm... Asmarael convinced me I should go after the Seraphim instead. What do I care about crimes committed? All I know is I was promised great rewards by this Spiderqueen!
3201349177	<b><i>13 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>The war against the alien intruders has been going well. With weaponry enhancements furnished by the Ancarian Unification Council's Ministry of Warfare based on the information we provided them, the soldiers in Seraphim Maria's armies are better able to take down our unwelcome guests. That's not to say there haven't been any significant losses to the Seraphim. It's been estimated that 10% of the Seraphim Corps has been killed off. At least the enhanced weaponry has somewhat stemmed the tide of losses.<br><br>The Ministry of Weaponry has decided to reassign my team. We are now going to be working on finding even better ways to eliminating the invaders. We've received reports from some of Seraphim units that said that T-Energy in its purest form seems to be lethal to the invaders. That is not too surprising, given that T-Energy is likewise toxic to Ancarian life as well. Though oddly enough, it's also well known that T-Energy also has the ability to stimulate life (or at least, life-like qualities) in dead tissues. In minute doses, pure T-Energy can cause severe mutations, psychotic behavior and ultimately death in otherwise normal beings. Fortunately, pure T-Energy is relatively rare and only occurs in a few places – like the eastern edge of Bluestone Lake. We will be focusing on T-Energy research – namely how to deliver pure T-Energy lethality to our invaders, wherever they roam.<br><br><b><i>15 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>We had a bit of an accident in the lab today. One of our rat specimens fell into our vat of pure T-Energy. He had gotten loose and in his efforts to escape, he fell directly into the vat.<br><br>On the bright side, it was almost a serendipitous moment. When we fished the rat out, we were expecting him to be mutated in the usual way, and to be quite dead... but he wasn't! Instead, the rat had lost all of its fur and was glowing a bright blue and was approximately twice his previous size. He was quite alive and kicking.<br><br>We've decided to keep our blue rat alive – as no one has ever quite seen anything of the sort.<br><br><b><i>18 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>Our blue rat has done some surprising things in the last few days. It seems to have gained a few abilities – much like the Elvish mage technique known as a "shadow step" – a sort of near instantaneous teleportation. It (and I say it, because our specimen no longer appears to be a "he") used the technique to get out of its cage to get at some food my assistant left on the counter across the room from it. We wouldn't have suspected our blue rat to have been the culprit if it wasn't for the fact that there were at least four pairs of eyes focused on it at the time. What we saw boggled the mind.<br><br>When my assistant confronted our rat, the rodent glared at him with a rather evil look and raised a paw toward him and took a swipe at his arm that nearly broke it in two. Amazing! Its beady red eyes were positively glowing like red hot coals. When it finished my assistant's lunch, the rat promptly used its shadow step move to return to its cage.<br><br><b><i>19 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>I decided to repeat the previous day's events with our blue rat again. This time, however, under more controlled conditions. This time, I had a large metal plate brought in and set it up so it would block the rat's line of sight with the counter where my assistant left his food the previous day. Then I brought in some leftovers – a rather aromatic Bengareshi Curry - and placed them on the counter. The rat got a whiff of the curry and immediately used its shadow step technique to escape his confines and raid the plate. Once the meal was finished, the rat returned to its cage the same way it escaped.<br><br>It would seem the rat has the ability to remember the exact layout of the laboratory so it didn't need line of sight to find its way to the food.<br><br><b><i>20 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>I decided to see how our specimen reacts to our enemies. I had the Seraphim bring in one of the invaders alive and placed him in restraints in the place of the metal plate. The food reward today was a nice Dryad Fish Stew. This time, however, I smeared some of the gravy from the stew onto the alien's body.<br><br>Our control rat – one that was a quite normal Ancarian specimen – tried to flee by hiding in its cage under the sawdust. Our blue rat, on the other hand, used its shadow step to escape its cage and went on what could best be called a rampage. What it did to the bipedal invader wasn't pretty. The rat's enhanced strength and claws dealt some serious damage to the alien's exoskeleton. We had wired the invader's jaw shut so it couldn't retaliate with its acidic poison.<br><br>The carnage didn't stop until I brought in the plate with the Dryad Stew and placed it on the counter. At that point, the blue rat abandoned the attack and went directly to feast on the food. The alien was quite dead by this point.<br><br>A side note: we've agreed to name our blue rodent specimen 'Algernon' after one of my lab assistant's grandfather – who was quite a wise elf in his day.<br><br><b><i>25 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>Algernon, our T-Energy infused rat specimen is doing well. Ten days after being immersed in the T-Energy vat and still ticking.<br><br>We decided over the past few days to attempt to reproduce the accident that caused Algernon to change. We've brought in a fresh supply of rodents and replenished our vat of T-Energy. Apparently, Algernon's dunking seems to have depleted our previously full vat by a third.<br><br>Before we did anything with the rats, we ran a standard genetic sampling study on the lot of them to see if there were any genetic factors involved in the change. Can't be too careful.<br><br>The first two rats merely mutated in the more traditional sense. They turned black and blue. They didn't become fully infused and died soon after their dunking. The third merely drowned in the vat without any change. We're obviously missing some key ingredient to make the transformation successful.<br><br><b><i>27 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>Success! We finally figured out why our attempts were failing. It would seem there was a short in the power outlet near the vat that energized the vat and the T-Energy inside. One of my assistants fixed the short soon after we fished Algernon from the vat. Once I was reminded of that, I had him undo the fix and we were able to create Ben, our second T-Energy infused rodent.<br><br>We've also found that Algernon and Ben do not seem to be able to get along. Ben seems to have gotten the same abilities as Algernon. When we brought in a plate of food for Algernon, Ben immediately shadow stepped to the plate and tucked in.<br><br>Algernon, of course, wasn't too thrilled with his new rival. He also shadow stepped to the plate and a fight ensued. A quick-thinking assistant – I've got to learn her name one of these days – quickly brought in a second plate and with the appearance of more food, the two rats decided fighting wasn't quite as important as was the eating.<br><br>After the plates were cleaned, (and I mean clean! They were spotless!) the two rodents gave each other a brief hiss and shadow stepped back to their cages.<br><br><b><i>28 Kuthar 4158</i></b><br><br>A representative of the Ancarian Unification Council's Ministry of Warfare stopped by today. Unfortunately, he had the bad taste to show up with a food stain on his tunic. Seems he was a bit of a slob at breakfast. When the two T-Energy infused rats got a whiff of his food stained shirt – they had the bad taste to shadow step out of their cages and immediately attacked the poor man. They bloody well tore a hole in his chest half way to his heart before they gave up and went back to their cages. This does not bode well. I think he was the deputy minister or some such. The damage done by the two was quite incredible. Nothing stopped their progress – neither clothing, nor skin, nor bone.<br><br><b><i>1 Tyrbor 4158</i></b><br><br>It seems the attack on the unfortunate minor official by our T-Energy infused pets did us a bit of a favor. He was part of a faction who would have rather invested our time and efforts in other directions. I think we're onto something. If only there were a way to better control our pets' appetites so they attack the invaders and not Ancarian citizens. Maybe if we used other species – ones better able to take orders and behave. We will have to expand our tests to bigger and better subjects.
3204424307	You there! My supervisor, Lieutenant Rinah wishes you to speak with you urgently! You can find her in the vaults of the temple behind me. You are free to access the area now.
3276898421	They look like the oldest book I've ever seen. Far older than anything in the central library at Thylysium. I need to read them to see what secrets they hold. They might have a clue to where I can find the Great Machine.
3368939606	The largest market in Artamark
3368939607	The DeMordrey seat of power
3368939608	Town on the border of the Human and Orc realms
3368939609	Peaceful retreat near the Bottomless Lake
3368939610	Quiet town on the Bluestone Lake
3368939714	Isolated spiritual enclave
3368939715	Home to a bygone Seraphim sisterhood
3368939716	Ruins northeast of Seraphim Tower
3368939717	Camp of the human resistance fighters
3368939718	Ancient home of the Nur-Trak clan
3368939719	A settlement of the Nameless Cult
3368939720	Village of Lizard people
3368939721	A troubled archaeological excavation site
3368939722	Town in southern Bengaresh
3368939723	The largest oasis in the Bengaresh Desert
3368939827	Deserted, crumbling ruins
3368939828	A recent settlement of human refugees
3368939829	Camp near the Great Machine entrance
3368939830	Zombie residence
3368939831	An old Dwarven route through the northern mountains
3461590814	This trip looks like it was a waste of time. The Great Machine isn't in the cave. It's just another model like the one I found on Seraphim Island. Now it's time to get out of here!
3494983484	Virtues of the Seraphim
3494983485	Sopor Aethernis
3494983487	Armaments of the Nine Hells
3494983488	Scourge of Lordaeron
3494983489	Memories of the Trees
3494983490	BerDaiPayn
3494983491	SinIthTer
3494983492	KilthEmAl
3494983493	YerLuvVun
3494983597	DisTrukXion
3494983598	ImMorTel
3494983599	TomMarWolOryDel
3494983600	KlaAtuVerAtaNikTuh
3494983601	Remnants of Drizzt
3494983602	Genesis Siderea
3494983603	Lara's Glad Rags
3494983604	Range Array
3494983605	Endijian's Heirlooms
3494996254	Chaoskampf
3494996255	Auspicious Powers
3494996256	Eternal Return
3494996257	Tooth and Nail
3494996258	Doom Guard Armor
3494996259	Kha-Beleth's Sovereignty
3494996260	Children of Asha
3494996261	Insignia Regis
3494996262	Flesh Eaters' Implements
3494996366	Disciples of the Architect
3494996367	The Night and The Silent Water
3494996368	Remnants of Glaurung
3494996369	The Judicator
3494996370	Disgraced Gods
3494996371	Undead Legionaire's Armaments
3494996372	Impressions of Sophia
3494996373	Crypt Raider's Artifacts
3494996374	The Wild Cat
3494996375	Frozen Gems
3494996479	Mage of the Spectrum
3494996480	Smoke Without Fire
3494996481	Mark of the Dragon
3494996482	Charo's Resplendence
3494996483	Silithar's Animus
3494996484	Khral's Eminence
3494996485	Gruma's Edict
3494996486	Soorn's Doombringer
3494996487	Instruments of the Assassin
3539255550	I met a Dryad today. She told me about a friend in trouble. She spoke of disappearances and murder, but could not shed light upon the whole story. She asked me to seek out Turok, an Orc that lives in the jungle. If am not sure where this is going, but I will look for Turok, he will surely be able to tell me more.
3553716196	I have a few familiars in the Senate. I plan to use that to negotiate peace with the nobility. The Inquisition has, as you know, spies everywhere. However, there are also a few people I know well enough to know that they will join our path. Your task is to seek out the guard on duty officer in the central prison, commander Amalia in the camp near Twainbrook, Inquisitor Tahlreth in Sloeford, and the Wall guard at the Great Wall and to bring them my plans. With them as our allies chances are very good. May the gods be with you on your mission.
3556488403	Yes! I have managed to defeat Asmarael. Though this was not an easy victory! I should tell Failitia the news.
3686672962	The Impostor
3687214128	Shelob
3687227349	Failitia
3687239900	Failitia
3687252891	Expedia
3687265430	www.frankrentmeister.info/mantisbt
3687265657	forum.sacred2.de
3687265658	forum.sacred2.com
3687265659	www.sacred-legends.de
3687265660	www.darkmatters.org
3687265661	www.sacredwiki.org
3687277972	Brian Dunkleman
3687291649	Tizz'Agoz
3687328943	Lightning Lord
3687328944	Lightning Lord
3687329847	Extremely Poor Farmer
3710702535	Failitia's Guard
3710702869	Failitia's Guard
3710702870	Failitia's Guard
3710702873	Failitia's Guard
3710702875	Failitia's Guard
3710702876	Failitia's Guard
3741180796	Asmarael is truly evil! I will have to fight her, as she will not stand down. Either her, or that Seraphim, I really do not care!
3745512471	Toren tells me that he's seen the Great Machine in a cave north of Bluestonbury. I find this hard to believe. You would think they would have put the Great Machine in a more secure location. But, it's a lead and I can't leave any stone unturned. I will head there now.
3818349887	Rinah is gone. Somewhere in the fray I must have lost her. But a guard knows how to fight back. I surely will get news of her soon.
3829041445	<AlignH Value=Center/><b><i>A Sword of Light and Darkness</b></i><br><br><AlignH Value=Left/>Tales of this weapon come from various legends of Artamark. Some accounts are conflicting, but the main plot is the same.Our story begins with a long, almost-unending war that took place in the land of Artamark during days past. Nobody remembers when it began, exactly, but the legend lives on. Back then, wars broke frequently between the ancient races, and the human land that borders both Nor Plat and Tyr Lysia often became a battlefield. This war was especially long and hard. A lot of lives ended because of it, a lot of places were ruined. Elves, Orcs and humans were fighting to either occupy or defend the lands. Some people say that during this war even the dwarves left their caves for the fight. The humans have no chance against more advanced elves, more furious orks and more skilled dwarves. They needed a miracle to survive this war. During this war the humans forgot about all the inner troubles and fought together, or worked together to prepare for the fight. So the most skilled weaponsmiths of the human lands gathered together in order to create an ultimate weapon, the one that would give their nation a chance in war.<br><br>During those days the Elven magic was so strong that it could stop any spell the human wizards could create. This new weapon, then, could not rely upon magic, but instead upon pure brute force. During those days the Dwarven armor crafting skills were supreme. So the new weapon should be able to avoid any armor and hit the target directly. During those days the Orcish furious assault was unstoppable. So the new weapon should be able to kill them before they move.<br><br>The best weaponsmiths of Artamark spent seven days trying to come up with the way to create such a weapon. They tried one idea after another, refusing to stop even for a minute, because every minute might be the last for their country. But their efforts were pointless, all the prototypes they created were not powerful enough. Then one of the youngest smiths, being disappointed as he was, left the forge. He was just standing outside and looking at the darkened skies, not knowing what to do next. Feeling small and helpless, he started to pray. He prayed to all the Gods he knew, he asked the Earth under his feet and the Sky above his head for help. He was so desperate that he noticed nothing but the black sky and shining stars. Then, one of the stars begin to move, almost as if it was answering his calls. It moved faster and faster, and suddenly fell from the sky, disappearing somewhere in the woods. The smith considered it a sign the Gods sent him, so he ran to the woods in a search for the falling star. After some hours he found it. It was not a star, but a piece of ore. It was as dark as a night and as hot as a fire. Without a shadow of a doubt, the young smith picked up this piece of ore, though it was heavy and burned his hands. He managed to carry it to the forge. By the time he came to the forge, all the weaponsmiths left their hammers and stood still, being sad and disappointed. When the young smith came to them shouting about the Gods' help, they decided that this piece of ore he brought was the last thing left to try. As it was not big, they melted and mixed it with the steel. The resulting metal was more firm and more ductile than the usual steel. They then used it to create a sword. Its dark blade was so strong and sharp, that it complied with all their demands. They named their creation 'Redeemer', because it was meant to save the land of Artamark.<br><br>The weaponsmiths proudly presented the Redeemer to the king of Artamark. Admiring the weapon, the king tried to lift the big and undoubtedly powerful sword. But he was unable to even move it. The same things that made the Redeemer able to crush any armor and to injure enemies badly also made it very big and heavy. Only the most skilled and trained warriors were able to use it in a fight. But to wield such a sword was an honor, so all the king's vassals tried to lift it and swing it a bit. But even those who managed to lift the sword, dropped it the very next moment.<br><br>Since all the nobles failed to lift the Redeemer, the king decided to take a look at the ordinary soldiers. The officers were ordered to fall their men in. All the soldiers were ordered to stand in order and not to move. Surrounded by his guards, the king was walking along the array, trying to notice if one of the soldiers differed from the others. Suddenly an elf appeared out of nowhere, Elven magic probably used to quickly help him appear instantly in front of the human king. He then threw a spell to the place where the king and his guards stood. The intruder's intentions were clear enough - he came to assassinate the king and to destroy the humans' last hope for victory. The king's guards were shocked by the spell and could not move. They were unable to stop the assassin in time. But at this moment one of the private soldiers left the order and rushed to the assassin. But before the elf managed to cast his next spell, the soldier lifted his sword and killed the intruder. This soldier disobeyed an order, but saved the king's life. The king was grateful and decided to talk to that brave soldier. 'What is your name?', the king asked. 'My name is Aarnum Richfield, my lord', answered the soldier while kneeling down before the king. 'You disobeyed your superior's order, Private Richfield. Why did you do so?', asked the kind trying to test the soldier. 'I did so because I serve not my superior, but you and the land of Artamark', answered Aarnum without having any doubts. The king was quite happy to see such loyalty. He decided that Aarnum's feat of arms should be rewarded. Since the king needed some allies among nobility, and his people needed heroes, he decided to bestow the small land and the title of Knight upon that soldier. Willing to show his gratitude immediately, the king asked Aarnum for his sword to knight him. Surprisingly, the soldier gave the king not a simple sword that were typical for human army, but some huge ancient-looking sword. He claimed this sword to be his heirloom. The king was surprised to see a sword that big and heavy. 'Who if not him', the king thought - and ordered to bring the Redeemer. 'If you could lift this sword, you would become a noble Knight and a hero of this land', he told Aarnum. The warrior took the sword and lifted it easily. It seemed to fit him perfectly...<br><br>The rest is history. Three months later the war was over. Humans managed to defend the land of Artamark, and being a kind person and a brave warrior, Aarnum made a good name for himself and proved that his sword is worth its name.<br><br>Sadly, the end of Sir Aarnum Richfield's life was not as bright as his young days. His sons who were about to inherit his name and land were nothing but a huge source of disappointment and worries. One of them was a weak airhead, the other was a wicked schemer, and none of them was the one Aarnum might be proud of. So just before his death, Sir Richfield said: 'I want only the ones who care about Artamark to wield my sword. I want the Redeemer to be earned, not inherited.' - and ordered to return the Redeemer to the king, hoping that the king would give this sword only to a true hero of the land.<br><br>The Redeemer spent many decades lying in the Royal Treasury. The kings of Artamark knew that their people would pay special attention to the one who would wield this weapon, so they did not want to give it away easily.<br><br>The time when the sword appeared again was a dark one for Artamark. But this time there were no intruders nor foreign enemies. The forces that tore the land apart were inside it. The powerful vassals of the king refused to obey the king's orders and continued fighting with each other. The civil war was slowly wiping out the human race. The king tried to settle the nobles down, but his authority was too low and his army was too little. He desperately needed an ally among the nobles. During that time, the most power of his vassals was Baron Johann DeMordrey, the owner of Skook's Corner. But the Baron was powerful enough to ignore the king completely. He wanted power, and he had a lot of it. One day the king found out that one of the Barons offered his corps to lay siege to the capital city of Griffinborough. His own army was too small to stand a siege, so he decided to ask Johann DeMordrey for help. Knowing Johann's thirst for power and fame, the king offered him a title of the First Knight and the Redeemer to boot. The next day Johann DeMordrey send his corps to assist the royal army. After the battle was over, the Baron became the Redeemer's new owner. That day was the last time when the king of Artamark actually ruled his land.<br><br>During the next years, the civil war stopped. But that was not because the peace came to the human land. That was because of fear. Everybody feared the actual ruler of Artamark. No, it was not the king, who could do nothing during these days, but Baron Johann DeMordrey. He was so cruel and stern, that the people called him Johann the Terrible. He could tolerate nobody who stood in his way. His corps immediately stopped all the attempts on mutiny. It was said that Johann enjoyed killing the enemy leaders himself, finishing them by his legendary sword. Because of it some people began to call the sword 'Dark Redeemer', but the ones who remembered its history continued calling it 'Redeemer', since it was known for bringing not only Darkness but also Light to the land of Artamark.<br><br>Twenty years passed, Johann the Terrible became older and could not react on all the events with his former quickness. Various new mutinies soon became more frequent. Once the Baron received news about a mutiny in the west lands and ordered his corps to move there. As always, he led his soldiers himself. The battle took place near the town of Wargfels. Luckily for all the people of Artamark, Baron Johann was killed in this battle.<br><br>His sword's fate remains uncertain. Some people say that it was lost in the battle and may be found somewhere in the land of Artamark. Others assume that one of the soldiers picked it and, following the legendary Sir Richfield's order, returned the Redeemer to the king. Some people even suspect that the legendary sword is hidden somewhere in the DeMordrey family castle...<br><br>Now the Redeemer, which witnessed the Light and the Darkness, which was used to save Life and to bring Death, lies somewhere, patiently waiting for its new owner. Only time will tell, what power this sword would serve the next time.
3901811847	FreaqZombie
4086113343	Identities Unveiled
4087645150	The conversation with Lieutenant Rinah took a surprising turn. Obviously there are still some representatives of the clergy, which are contrary to the dark machinations of the Grand Inquisitor.<br><br>Rinah asked me to accompany her to the senior Inquisitor Monwarion. From him I should learn more.
4103323018	Greetings. I'm Rinah, Lieutenant of the Inquisition Guard of Thylysium. Good thing you have decided to come to us, because the Inquisition urgently needs your help. Before you hit your decision, I should inform you that the clergy has split into two groups.<br><br>Follow me to senior Inquisitor Monwarion. He will tell you the exact details.
4128292115	Kill the Lightning Lord!<br><br>Hello, there! My name's Tizz'Agoz. I hail from Hissil'Ta, to the south of here. I was sent to clear out a particularly troublesome lightning elemental that came down from the mountains and has been terrorizing the villages nearby. I've never seen an elemental like this one. I think the miasma in the swamps has stirred it up.<br><br>You look like you know how to handle yourself around monsters. Maybe you will have better luck than me trying to drive it away. Be careful - I already tried to fight the thing once, and it nearly shocked me senseless.
4205999729	AgrimOnyx
4205999730	Blood Onyx
4206038045	Lightning Lord
4227877878	That wasn't entirely a waste of time. The machine wasn't in there but these books seem to be very, very old. They might have a clue.
4254592930	The priest was relieved to learn that the Dragon was put down. Now, I should be able to browse his stock of specialized mounts. I wonder what kind of creatures he's bred?
4272337543	A guard of the Inquisition has informed me that Lieutenant Rinah wants to talk to me. I wonder what an officer of the Inquisition could possibly want from me. I guess there's only one way to find out.
