0020251688	Impulse - Sends out two pulses. Overall damage is increased by 30% but split between the two novas.
0020251913	Flux - Increases the base magic damage of inflicted by 66%.
0026077106	What? YOU? Don't hurt me! You... creature! I had hoped you were dead! Well... you are. But not really. You weren't satisfied with slaughtering an entire village, were you? They say you were executed, sent on a suicide mission.<br>Spare me and I will give you documents about the Necromancer conspiracy in the capital.
0058995549	Exploit - Each party member receive a portion of the damage intended for the Inquisitor (4.9% + 0.1% per level).
0104247005	Conviction - Increases the Inquisitor's base Willpower attribute by 35 + 10 per level.
0154583344	Impale - Adds a chance to inflict deep wounds, which decrease the opponent's base hitpoints by 8% for 10s (20% + 0.1% chance per level).
0169999160	Perforate - Adds a chance to inflict deep wounds, which decrease opponent health by 8% for 10s (24.7% + 0.3% per level).
0169999161	Envenom - Converts physical weapon damage into poison (50% + 1% per level).
0172928357	Energy Shield Lore
0254501903	Antimagic - Adds a chance to reflect incoming spells (30% + 0.8% per level).
0301665375	Vortex - Increases the radius of the Maelstrom by 50%.
0312890711	Determination - Adds armor resistances against all damage types for the doppelganger (7.5 + 5.5 per level).
0341111393	<b><i><AlignH Value=Center/>The Study of Anatomy</b></i><br><br><AlignH Value=Left/>The science of anatomy is the study of the structures of living beings. It considers the mechanical functions of muscles and bones as well as the location of organs and their functions. A solid knowledge of anatomy is essential for any kind of healer. Anyone who deals with anatomy needs a keen mind, a quick wit and sharp knives. Not feeling queasy easily is also advantageous.<br><br>Although anatomy is one of the basics of the lore of healing, scientists dealing with this branch of science are often sneered at, belittled as "squints" or indeed "ghouls" and some people even imply that they lack the intelligence to cure diseases and that is why they cut open dead bodies instead. Still, despite all the ridicule and the abuse, anatomy is a complex and serious science.<br><br><b><i>Famous Anatomists of Ancaria<br></b></i><br><i>Kyrilath (561 - 352, Old Time)</i><br>Kyrilath is without a doubt the most famous anatomist of Ancaria. His works "Fauna Ancaria" as well as "Mechanics of the Body" are standard references. Some of his lesser-known books were written in a more popular scientific way and include "How to Disassemble a Skeleton" and "Sections on Your Kitchen Table - A Compendium for Hobby Anatomists." Least of all known is the fact that Kyrilath even ventured into the field of literature: His novel "Pighead" describes the fictitious conversations of an aging scientist with a skeleton. In his lifetime, Kyrilath went on three major journeys. During these journeys, he carried out extensive examinations and he drew very detailed sketches. At the age of 209 he tragically died during a swimming accident. One of the wings in the University of Thylysium is named after him.<br><br><i>Sebathiano (1042 - 742, Old Time)</i><br>The fact that the science of anatomy is often sneered at and even classed as somewhat disreputable is in part due to Sebathiano and his life's works.<br>Sebathiano was a mix of researcher, adventurer, mystic and (probably) necromancer. During his extensive travels he visited all known continents and carried out studies in almost all scientific and non-scientific fields. Anatomy was one of his passions. No other researcher ever cut open as many bodies as he did. Some reports say that Sebathiano even ventured onto raging battlefields in order to examine the fallen (and in some cases not quite so fallen) bodies right on the spot. Cemeteries and morgues were reputedly also some of his favorite locations to acquire objects for his studies. Many scholars of his time claimed that he was on the verge of insanity. They also accused him of merely using his anatomy research as an excuse to further his true interest, which was necromancy. However, he always succeeded in rebutting these accusations while he was alive.<br><br>Sebathiano died under mysterious circumstances during an experiment while attempting to channel lighting into a dead body.<br><br><i>Enyaris (15 - Present, New Time)</i><br>Enyaris is said to be one of the masterminds of modern anatomy in the academies of Ancaria. He was the first to take the trouble and catalog all known studies and works of this field; he corrected all mistakes and then merged all the knowledge into one resource. The result of years of work is the "Complete Bestiary of Ancaria", which describes in fifteen volumes the body structures of all known living beings. Furthermore, he considered philosophical and anthropological questions. Sometimes, he refers to himself as the "possibly last real researcher."
0394361330	Double Attack - Adds an extra ranged projectile, or a chance for melee double hits (15% + 0.1% per level).
0394361443	Double Attack - Adds an extra ranged projectile, or a chance for melee double hits (15% + 0.1% per level).
0394361556	Hemorrhage - Increases the chance to inflict open wounds by 15% + 0.1% per level.
0399181749	I retrieved the amulet. Looks pretty valuable to me. I'd do better to sell it for some gold.
0479802523	Ravage - Increases the damage frequency by 25% (+0.2 hits per second).
0508441554	<AlignH Value=Center/><b><i>How to Deal with Undead? A Guideline</i></b><br><br><AlignH Value=Left/><i>"He moved towards me - swaying, his body oddly twisted and dislocated. His staring, squinting look appeared to go right through me. Some strange and indiscernible green liquid oozed from his mouth while he permanently attempted to speak. I drew my sword but then I realized it was not a zombie, it was the captain who was completely drunk on his way to his cabin."</i><br>(from the travelogues of Nayjol the Adventurer)<br><br>Every adventurer has heard of them and many have already encountered them: Marauding zombies on derelict cemeteries, erratic skeletons on historic battlefields, vampires in their shape shift forms as wolves or bats or ghosts doing their boring spooking routines; undead come in many shapes and forms.<br><br>Undead creatures are not only extremely obnoxious, they are also classed as highly dangerous! Many unprepared adventurers underestimated the danger and lost their lives to the 'un-life'. This guide was written to assist the aspiring adventurer in his dealings with undead creatures. "Know thy enemy!" is our motto. Well then, let's meet the enemy!<br><br>The lowest form of undead creatures are skeletons, zombies and mummies. All these forms are reanimated bodies without mind or intellect. Reanimating bodies is the simplest form of necromancy, basically dead easy (pun intended) for any conjurer of death. This is probably the reason why these kinds of undead creatures are encountered more often than the other, more complex variations.<br><br>The rules of conduct while dealing with skeletons, zombies or mummies are pretty straightforward: If you wish to avoid them, do not go near any cemeteries or battle fields. Catacombs and dungeons are also preferred habitats of these creatures.<br><br>If an encounter is inevitable, your choice of actions is rather limited. Each and any attempt to lead a conversation will be futile; thus, you will have to resort to pure violence. However, do be careful! Zombies, and even more so skeletons, are tough opponents. They are held together by necromantic magic and thus, they are able to regenerate severe wounds and even severed limbs within a short amount of time. The magic will only dissipate when the bodies have been completely dismembered and only then will their remains dissolve.<br><br><Image=zombie.tga/><br> <br>While skeletons and zombies are rather dumb, ghouls do have some sort of ability to think. Ghouls are creatures, which are half dead and half alive. Trapped in this interstage they wander the world without aim, feed on carrion and human bodies and they are typically timorous. Still, attempting to solve an imminent conflict with ghouls by verbal means is also futile. Your first choice should be drawing your weapon.<br><br><i>"'Approximately three hundred years ago a blow like that could have killed me!' ranted the ghost before he disappeared through the closed door and left me standing with my sword in my hand."</i><br>(from the travelogues of Nayjol the Adventurer)<br><br>Ghosts and apparitions are bodiless and as such the exact opposite of the bodied undead such as zombies, skeletons and mummies. Here, only the ethereal part of a being has been reanimated. Ghosts and apparitions are thinking beings - often even capable of speaking - created by a complicated focus of necromantic energy.<br><br>Despite - or because of - their lack of bodies, ghosts and apparitions are dangerous opponents. Average weapons do not have any impact on ghosts. If you intend to stand your ground against a ghost, you will require magic or at least magical weapons. That is the only way these beings can be hurt.<br><br>Vampires are the ultimate form of undead existence. They are free, independent and thinking beings with supernatural abilities and powers. They are not created by necromancy; instead, they create themselves. Nobody knows where they come from, yet they exist. And they are extremely dangerous!<br><br>Not many adventurers can claim that they encountered a vampire and lived to tell the story. Evidently, a wooden stake, driven through the heart of a vampire will paralyze the undead creature. Furthermore, beheading a vampire will kill it. Contrary to popular belief the use of garlic, holy water and escaping across running waters are all ineffective according to several sources.
0583874142	I've been asked to get this dead woman's amulet and take it to her daughter.
0617970567	The Study of Anatomy
0651361835	Salvo - Fires two successive bolts. Overall damage is increased by 30% but split between the two bolts.
0686439080	Enemy Kills
0716579594	A rapid shot with ice bullets. Each bullet has a chance to bounce to up to 2 additional opponents nearby.
0842470957	Elite - Increases attack and defense values by 50% + 0.2% per level.
0842471070	Healing - Increases hitpoint regeneration by 8 hp/s + 2 hp/s per level.
0842471183	Aegis - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 33% + 0.1% per level.
0842471184	Leadership - Increases attack and casting speed by 10% + 0.2% per level.
0847253497	Guard - Decreases opponents' chance to cause secondary damage effects by 20% + 0.2% per level.
0961848109	Volatile - Increases the destroyers' base fire damage by 68%.
1069962370	Escape - The High Elf breaks all rooting effects while teleporting.
1084250567	We are all glad this is over! Failitia was overjoyed. A good day today!
1153331667	Intensify - Increases the damage frequency of Furious Emblazer by 50% (+1.0 hits per second).
1177892505	Notes of Psychiatrist Hergabol Chambers
1198637220	Avoidance - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 3% + 2% per level.
1244319911	Demon Cleaver
1244331769	Iridescent Spire
1244357307	The Study of Anatomy
1244357421	Notes of Psychiatrist Hergabol Chambers
1244370080	Endijian's Glaive
1244370865	Eternal Peace Pipe
1244395959	Assassin's Fang
1244395960	Assassin's Skean
1244409291	Charo's Gleaming Fist
1244421265	Soorn's Pious Blade
1245800655	Book 4: Guidebook of the Huntress
1320200592	Annul - Archimedes Beam dispels the opponent's permanent buffs.
1370795561	Intensity - Increases the chance for critical hits by 14% + 0.5% per level.
1370795562	Sicken - Increases the chance to poison opponents by 24.5% + 0.5% per level.
1370795674	Splash - Adds a chance to also damage opponents next to the target (60% + 0.3% per level).
1370795787	Contaminate - Inflicts additional poison damage over time (4.0/s + 2.0/s per level).
1389434280	Readiness - Increases the Shadow Warrior's base defense value by 10 + 5 per level.
1397431068	Spite - Knocks the weapon from the opponent's hand, disarming him for the duration.
1434169448	Confidence - Increases the Inquisitor's evade chance by 25% + 0.5% per level.
1469480446	Edged - Increases the weapon damage inflicted by 20% + 0.1% per level.
1573565684	Radius - Increases the effective angle of Gust of Wind to 240 degrees.
1626398677	Increases resistance against magic spells and secondary damage effects (burn, poison, freeze, weaken). Increases damage dealt by lightsabers. Increases energy shield points.
1671186197	<b>Goblinoids</b><br><br>The Goblinoid classification not only covers Goblins, but also Orcs, Ogers, and Trolls. Some (usually older) books on anatomy also refer to Kobolds as Goblinoids, but this is obviously wrong.<br><br>Anatomically speaking, Goblinoids differ only insignificantly from Humanoids; every major anatomical characteristic is shared by both classes. The anatomical separation of Goblinoids and Humanoids is however not based on science, but rather on history. The famous anthropologist and naturalist Kyrilath was the first to classify every living being in Ancaria (published in "Fauna Ancaria"). His hatred of Orcs and Goblins was so intense that he couldn't bear the thought of belonging to the same class, so he simply created a new one. His classifications are still in use today and are accepted as true by many.<br><br>Eccentric chauvinisms aside, one can find a number of anatomical differences between both classes:<br><br>Goblinoid beings - just as Humanoids - possess a pair of arms and a pair of legs which are connected to the torso. The head (with two eyes, two ears, a nose, and a mouth) sits on the shoulders. They usually walk upright using their two legs.<br>If one takes a closer look, it becomes obvious that Goblinoid skulls are broader and more compact than Humanoid skulls. Their jaw is strong and prominent, their canines are long and thick. The neck tends to be short and much thicker than a Humanoid neck; sometimes the head seems to rest right on the shoulders with no neck visible at all. Goblinoid arms are very long when compared to legs and torso. Goblinoids also tend to be bow legged with outward pointing feet.<br>Shoulders are strong and muscular. Goblinoids are overall very brawny. To compensate for this added mass their bodies tend to be quite short. Goblinoids, especially Orcs, are physically well suited for fast and powerful movements; however, they do not cope well with longer stretches of physical exertion.<br><br>As mentioned earlier, Kobolds are not members of the Goblinoid class, but shall be described here anyway as they are often mentioned in this context.<br><br>Kobold anatomy is characterized by extreme disproportions. The head seems much too large for the body, the arms are long and thin, the legs short. The most prominent feature of a Kobold is the long, crooked nose. Many myths and legends have sprung up about this olfactory organ. In the southern desert regions dried and ground Kobold nose is still being used as a cure for certain "male problems". Because of this superstition Kobolds have become almost extinct there.<br>The weight of the Kobold head leads to a shortening of the spine which causes a chronic disease with an unfavorable prognosis called Kobold Back. Nearly all Kobolds from a certain age on suffer from this condition. Statistics claim that almost 26% of all Kobolds die of Kobold back. The numbers for heroes who die trying to perform heroics and the number of adventurers falling victim to their adventures are almost as high.
1760150820	Disarm - Knocks the weapon from the opponent's hand for 15s.
1840213650	Relay - Increases the effective angle by 38%, hitting more opponents at once.
1840213764	Tumble - Knocks the weapon from the opponent's hands, disarming him for 10s.
1855643911	The man was true to his word. This oil has made all the difference. Even better is this power source he had on hand.
1875909638	Ardor - Decreases the regeneration time of all combat arts while Dashing Alacrity is active by 20% + 0.2% per level.
1875909639	Vigor - Increases the Seraphim's hitpoint regeneration by 2.5 hp/s + 1.5 hp/s per level.
1875909751	Reprisal - The Seraphim inflicts more damage as she loses health (50% + 2.5% per level, max damage at 25% health).
1885852867	Elvin Mehmedagic<br>Naw,we're in a meeting.
1901875519	Follow the path north to the Crystal Caves!<br><br>Good, I accept your promise. Follow the path leading to the north, it will take you straight to the Crystal Caves.
1914031335	Chain Reaction - Adds a 90% chance to chain to 3 additional opponents.
1914031448	Chain Reaction - Adds a 90% chance to chain to 3 additional opponents.
1931810944	Disarm - Knocks the weapon from the opponent's hand for 5s.
1931811170	Chain - Adds an 80% chance to chain lightning to 5 additional opponents.
1951118777	Calls forth two earth elemental protectors that can slow enemies and heal themselves.
2096824982	Expansion - Increases the radius of Mind Strike by 230%, hitting multiple opponents per cast.
2155063465	A toxic, radioactive attack using T-Energy that severely damages the opponent's genes and leaves them sickened.
2192772076	The modifier "Chance to Bypass Armor" gives a chance that all the damage from a given attack will ignore the opponent's armor resistances.
2223524072	Knockback - Adds a chance to knock back opponents (25% + 0.5% per level).
2223524297	Inflamed - Inflicts additional fire damage with each hit.
2226285074	CM-Patch 0160, EE v3.2
2227688677	The horse leaps forward, thereby breaking roots, slowing opponents, and overcoming obstacles in its way.
2390214356	Book 4: Guidebook of the Huntress
2428246063	Succession - Adds an extra ranged projectile, or a chance for melee double hits (20% + 0.1% per level).
2428246177	Enfeeble - Decreases the opponent's defense value for 15s by 10% + 0.1% per level.
2428246290	Indentation - Decreases the opponent's physical armor for 15s by 50% + 1% per level.
2440350996	Find and kill Haenir.<br><br>Very good. As we suspected, Haenir is no god. He has a mortal form hidden away in the ice caves. You earned his trust. Now go and terminate his existence.
2498623698	Rapid Fire - Increases the attack speed of all weapons by 7.4% + 0.1% per level.
2554397577	Unbound - The Shadow Warrior breaks all rooting effect when leaping.
2672774360	Go to the island of the Dryads and retrieve the key to unveil the hub<br><br>I see, they moved the machine. Very clever of those Temple Guardians. Well then, this pretty much determines our next step. Go to the Dryads and acquire the key. And don't waste any time. One of my spies is on the island already. Meet him for further instructions.
2696218274	Troll
2700444811	Random Feature #1011
2700444812	Bug #45456 not found
2700444813	Use Stdheader.h instead
2700444814	Memory Overflow
2700444815	Unable to acquire devices
2700444816	E_OUTOFMEMORY
2700444817	DefragVidMem
2700444818	Out of heap memory
2700444819	Guru Meditation
2700444820	Unknown error
2700444924	Random Feature #43327
2700444925	Access violation
2700444926	Stack overflow
2700444927	Cannot run in DOS mode
2700444928	Missing [unknown] DLL
2700444929	Division by zero
2700444930	Fdiv
2700444931	Bug_6097
2700444932	Bug_6098
2700444933	Bug_6099
2700456676	Bug_6100
2700456677	Bug_6101
2700456678	Bug_6102
2700456679	Brainbug
2700482558	Gartor
2700676140	Enforce - Increases the weapon damage inflicted by 20% + 0.1% per level.
2703394006	Du'Rach Tribe Leader
2703419655	Du'Rach Tribe Leader
2704799042	Gartor
2805734906	Quick Mind - Increases casting speed by 15% + 0.2% per level.
2818642694	Enemy Kills
2834399198	Thank you. You always were a good comrade. I don't have much I can give you. My luck in games is very fickle. But I still have your old battle gauntlets. I could never bring myself to gamble them away. Please, take them, along with my gratitude.
2901796401	Oops! That was nothing. The dealer has left. Permanently. How infuriating.
2906521338	Singe - Adds fire damage to the thorns (33% of base physical damage).
2945371754	Ice Bullets - Increases the base ice damage of each bullet by 100%.
2945371755	Ricochet - Adds a 60% chance for the bullet to bounce to 1 additional opponent.
2945371868	Ricochet - Adds a 60% chance for the bullet to bounce to 1 additional opponent.
2945371980	Ice Bullets - Increases the base ice damage of each bullet by 100%.
2970731069	Capacitor - Decreases the cooldown gradually as Propelled Levitation levels up.
3045447100	Steadfast - Increases the Seraphim's base Willpower attribute by 35 + 10 per level.
3045447326	Improved Mirror - Adds a chance to reflect spell damage (50% + 1% per level).
3220710317	Scales - Increases the total armor resistances of the Berserk by 7.5% per level.
3220710543	Fatal - Increases the total damage of the Berserk by 7.5% per level.
3258739913	Determination - Adds armor resistances against all damage types for the doppelganger (7.5 + 5.5 per level).
3265225288	Icy Circle - Increases the radius of Frost Flare by 133%, hitting more opponents at once.
3281285300	Getaway - The Shadow Warrior breaks all rooting effects when beginning the charge.
3344668745	Obscure - Adds a chance to block ranged weapon damage (20% + 1% per level).
3435004724	Easiness - Further decreases the regeneration time of all combat arts by 15% + 0.5% per level.
3435004837	Defiant - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 20% + 0.5% per level.
3435004951	Proficiency - Increases the duration of Acute Mind by 10s.
3438024785	The Dryad's hunting prowess grants her increased attack speed and attack value with all weapons. This buff also adds a chance that opponents will drop shrunken heads.
3566457143	Distract - Decreases opponents' total speed within the area of effect by 20% + 0.2% per level.
3643706374	Ker, the Goddess of Chaos, conjures a mighty Sakkara demon from the depths. The demon is bound by a temporary magic shackle and thus condemned to serve. However, if it is not destroyed, this dark creature will eventually break free and escape back to the shadows in a fiery explosion.
3693087582	Shockwave - Increases the radius of the energy blast by 33%.
3698214482	Life Energy - Further increases hitpoint regeneration by 1.5 hp/s + 1.0 hp/s per level.
3698214594	Resilience - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 30% + 0.3% per level.
3734181077	Strong Voice - Increases the area of effect by 100%, converting more opponents at once.
3771455487	Damn! That ghost woman found me and laid a curse on the amulet. I can't seem to take it off! I need to find someone who can lift the curse right away.
3829990565	Recovery - Restores the Dryad's hitpoints by 14.9% + 0.1% per level.
3829990679	Encroach - Doubles the radius of the rooting effect against opponents.
3829990791	Refresh - Restores the Dryad's hitpoints by 14.9% + 0.1% per level.
3829990792	Escape - The Dryad breaks all rooting effects during her flight.
3832339230	Thank you. You always were a good comrade. I don't have much I can give you. My luck in games is very fickle. But I still have your old battle gauntlets. I could never bring myself to gamble them away. Please, take them, along with my gratitude.
3859027682	Unnatural Selection - Inflicts double damage when opponent health falls below 50%.
3910091551	Legion - Conjures yet another spectral soldier.
3950610734	Protection - Increases the base physical armor resistance by 50%.
3950610847	Protection - Increases the base physical armor resistance by 50%.
3950610961	Runes - Increases the chance to block spells by 25% + 0.3% per level.
4011807218	Avoidance - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 3% + 2% per level.
4036742180	Intent - Increases the chance for critical hits by 9.9% + 0.1% per level.
4036742294	Envenom - Adds base poison weapon damage to Frenzied Rampage.
4036742406	Double Attack - Adds a chance for melee double hits (20% + 0.1% per level).
4048187119	<AlignH Value=Center/><i>Ker</i><br><br>Ker is the Goddess of Chaos. She is the destroyer, the bringer of evil, and the guardian of darkness.<br><br><br><Image=gott_chaos_sakkaradaemon.tga/><br>Grants:<i>Sakkara<br></i><br>From the dimensional depths Ker conjures a demon which will assist in the fight. The demon will persist until it is either destroyed or succeeds in breaking free of its magic shackles, escaping back to the shadows in a fiery explosion.
4054639731	While I've encountered a fair share of disturbed individuals in my 14-year-long career at the Skullsberg Asylum, my current patient, Archaon Kirby, seems to be a hopeless case indeed. A former high-ranking Priest of Lumen of considerable wealth, he had developed an unhealthy habit of smoking narcotic spices, resulting in deteriorating mental faculty and an eventual state of severe paranoid delusion. At the time of being entrusted to our care, Kirby was already clinically insane. He now spends his time constantly raving about the End Times and some One-Eyed King, called Abishai, destined to rule them all. He also mumbles something about miniatures, about us all being chess pieces in a Great Game. My methods fail at treating the poor fellow, I've got to consult my peers in Thylysium... 
4181977903	Take the scroll to the learned Wentelien!<br><br>The text is written in an old language that I am not familiar with. Fortunately I know a dead language expert, and he is staying in the desert village of Nambarah right now. His name is Wentelien and we've worked together in the past. He's pretty conceited, but he really does know a lot about old languages and characters. We have to show him our scroll!
4194296018	Antidote - Decreases the impact and duration of detrimental effects by 20% + 0.5% per level.
4246223387	Master - Decreases the regeneration penalty of Protector by 50% + 1% per level.
4286179394	Claressa is back with her father. Garnet gave me my old battle gauntlets in return. I can almost feel my memories return as I slip them on. My task here is completed.
